<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-telephone-invention</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014896/1876-11-18/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Philadelphia+Bell+Telephones+Alexander</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AUDIBLE SPEECH CONVEYED TWO MILES BY TELEGRAPH
The Boston Advertiser prints an in
teresting account ot an experiment m
carrying on a conversation by word of
mouth over telegraph wire, made by
Alexander Graham Bell and Thomas
Watson. Telephones were placed at
either end of a telegraph line owned
by th "Walworth Manufacturing Com
nanv. extendiuir from their office in
Boston to their factory in Cambridge
port, a distance of about two miles.
The comnativ's battery, consisting of
nine Daniels cells, was removed from
tlie circuit and another ot ten carbon
elements substituted. Articulate con
versation then took placo through the
wire. The sounds, at first taint and
indistinct, b came suddenly loud and
intelligible. Mr. Bell in Boston and
Mr. "Watson in Cambridge took notes
of what was said and heard, and the
comparison of the two records shows
that the transmission was almost per-
fectlv accurate. Conversation was car
ried on for about half an hour, gener-
ally in an ordinary tone of voice, but
often in whispers. Miie creuit oi tins
important discovery is due to Mr. Bell</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032573/1877-04-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Wonderful&st=text&r=0.709,1.029,0.235,0.192,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A WONDERFUL INVENTION
	A Wonderful Invention.
Thrco vears ago the Herald predict
ed that 'the time would come when
the human voice aud musical sound
could be carried long distances over
electric wires, that the prima douna
who sang in New York could be heard
in the music halls of San Francisco.
The Boston Olobeoi Tuesday, has a
dispatch three-quarters of a column
long, which was spoken in Salem and
heard and printed in Boston. Prof.
G. A. Bell, the inventor of the won
derful system, gave a lecture about
the telephone "m Salem, and to illus
trate the working capacity, he had the
operator in Boston give the audience
the news from Washington. Every
word was heard all over the hall, and
the spectators wore so astonished that
thev broke into applause, and, what is
marvellous, the applause was heard
in the Boston office, eighteen miles
away. The Globe says: "Coughing
and singing were then heard, and a
varictv of questions were then asked
from the Salem end, and the news
came fleeting along that the engineers
of the Boston aud Maine railroad had
struck. General Cogswell asked if
trains were running; the answer was
clear and distinct that they were not
at half past five o'clock. Pro. Bell in
troduced the Rev. E. C. BoIle, who
said, 'I shake hands with you cordial
ly in imagination, twenty miles away.'
The Rev. E. S. Atwood akcd, 'Doe
it rain 'It docs not in Boston,' was
Mr. Watson's answer. Pro. Gage, tho
electrician, then spoko through the
telephone, endeavoring to have his
voice recognized. This could not bo
done, as Mr. Watson was not familiar
with tho voice. Mr. Shaje Zsawa was
recognized, Mr. Wattou being perfect
ly familiar with his tones. One of the
assistant in Boston then said that
'Hold tho Forf would bo sung in Bos
ton, and the tunc which followed was
readilv recognized. Prof. Bell closed
his lecture bv briefly staling the prac
tical uses to whit-h ho was confident
the telephone could be applied.
Hearty applause was afforded the lec
turer as he finished, and people flocked
about the stage in large numbers to
more closely examine the wonderful
instrument that had placed them iu
audible communication with people
nearly twenty -miles away. The lec
ture and experiment were an unquali
fied success." New York Herald.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1877-03-31/ed-1/?sp=2&q=telephones+TELEPHONE+telephone&r=-0.079%2C0.491%2C0.838%2C0.685%2C0&st=text</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE TELEPHONE
	A TELEPHONE FUNNEL.
Ro, on a sultry Sunday morning, hotter according
to the thermometer than any day before it last year,
a small group of gentlemen entered the Main Build-
ing and stationed themselves in the gallery at the
east end. The party divided, and half went to each
end of the gallery. The great organ was between,
and neither half of the party could hear or sce the
other. Then Prof. A. Graham Bell brought out his
telephone. Wires for telegraphing were laid along
ihe gallery; a battery was set at work, anda contin.
uous current was sent along the line. The stations
n this line were only two; one at each end of the
gallery. At each station there was a little, ordinary
electro-magnet, such as people see usually on the
~able in a small telegraph office, and are in general
familiar with. Beside the magnet there wae nothing
except a fow funnels, These were of different shapes,
but they agreed in each having one end eovered
with stretehed parchiment, like a drum-head. On
4he center of each of these drum-heads, oatside, a
small plate of metal, G. was cemented fast. The
Jdiagram hows a more elaborate form of the funnel,
one that is provided with a movable ring or hoop
(below the letter A) which can be adjusted by set-
screws, H, H. By these means the parchment, F, IY,
over the end of the funnel, can be made tighter or
jooser. ln the earlier stages of the invention the
sonnd. The instructions for nse were very simple.
The sender of a message was to talk into ene funnel
the receiver was to apply the other funnel to his ear,
Fach was to hold his funnel so that the parchment
wonld be opposite the poles of the electro-maunet,
and very close to them; just so that the little picee
of metal, G, mounted on the parchment, should not
yuite touch the poles.
THE WILE SPEAKS WITH HUMAN VOICE,
The Emperor of Brazil, who had joiued the party
by special invitation, was offered the opportunity of
Yeading off in the experiments, but Le courteously
-vaived the precedence. Among the first to make
Yhmself Leard and recognized through the wire was
Prof. J. I. Hilgard. The friends of that genial pro-
fessor will readily imagine how his eyes twinkled
as he put the funnel to his lips and uttered in it the
words
“Dr. Draper! Dr. Draper! Do you hear me
yr. Draper was standing at the other end of the
gallery, holding a funnel to his oar.
“Why!” he exelaimed, That's Hilgard's voice.
pow it by the accent.”
fact, pecaliarities of accent and inflections of
voice were given at least quite as plainly as svl-
tables, The Scotch pronunciation of Sir William
homsen was recognized at ounce; Prof. Watson,
«he able-bodied astronomer of Ann Arbor, carried
vn a vigorous conversation with him. Prof, Mor-
+on of Hoboken obtained a hearing withont diflienity;
iether Prof. F. A. P. Barnard did, is more than
doubtful, There Lad been many difterent opinicus
among these experts as to the possibilities of the in-
strament. Some of the professors thonght it would
only give tones and intervals of speech; one was auite
sure that it would fail with certain vowels; another
-vas equally certain that it would be tripped up by
consonants. Nobody expected it to do what it actnally
Jid—to give the whole sound of voice aud words
aaturally. Sir William Thomson tested it carefully
on these points, One of the party took from his
socket a TripUNE and read from it, into the funnel,
rarvions paragraphs, It was the paper of the previous
Monday. June 26. The Democratic Convention was
shen in session at Sf. Louis. One of the paragraphs
vas from the St. Louis dispatches of Tne TRIBUNE,
and began, “8. 8. Cox has arrived.” The sole ad-
verse criticism of Sir William Thomson on this read-
jug was that he did not hear the “8, 8.” distinctly.
Another paragraph which was plainly heard through-
out, was from the Foreign Summary in the same
paper, containing the words “The Americans in
London are preparing to celebrate the Fourth of
uly.” 1tis not necessary to repeat here the com-
pliments to Dom Pedro that were wafted on the wire,
nor his amiable replies. Neither would it be profita-
ble to report the chaff which passed between the
professors, such as:
“When you go home you can tell o’ fun on the
telephone.”
“No more o that, Hal! Already this thing takes
my breath away.”
't may be hoped that the whole party, after this
dip into the mysteries of nature, tarned more
heartily to those of religion and spent the afternoon
in church.
A TELEPHONE CIRCUIT.
Flow and why does the telephone transmit the
voice? This question could be answered at almost
auy length. 1f the reader should wade into the liter-
ature of acoustic and electrie discovery, taking such
excellent guides as Helmholtz and Faraday, he would
probably be surprised at its amount and extent, He
would be likely also to find the waters very deep
and the bottom somewhat uncertain, before he
reached dry land and a clear theory- of the tele.
phone. As to construction, Prof. Bells instrament
js simple enough. In the diagram, a continuous
flow of electricity is supposed to be proceeding
along the wire, from one of the poles of the battery
through the electro-magnet BB, and the cup-like
receiver D (having a vibrating lid), and finally back
again to the other pole of the battery. I'lie metallic
receiver D is said to be more effective than the
stretched membrane; practically it combines the
funne!, the membrane, and the electro-maguet in a
single contrivance. It is described as being itself a
subular electro-mmaguet formed of a single helix
NEW-YORK DAILY TRIBUNE, 8
ATURDAY, MARCH 31, 1877.—WITH SUPPLEMENT.
eased in soft iron. The lid is represented as only in
part secured at the edge, and it is capable of vibra-
tion, being attracted or repelled when a current is
passing through the helix. The thickness of the lid
isabout that of cartridge paper. In vibratingit gives
out sound. [his part of the invention is attributed
to M. Nicles, and is 25 years old. In some recent
descriptions of Prof. Bell's apparatus a thin metallic
disk 1s also referred to as having been used for receiv-
ing the soungs instead of a stretched membrane. The
upper wire E, as shown in the diagram, is a return
wire to complete the circuit. The return wire is
not needed where connection with the earth can be
made at the ends of the line, as it is in the ordinary
practice of telegraphy..
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE WIRE,
When the small piece of metal, G, fig. 1,
that is mounted on the membrane A, is brought
near to the poles of the electro-magnet BE,
there is a change produced in the strength
of the current which is all the time pass-
ing along the line. This can be very easily proved.
Suppose that at the point X a galvanometer is intro-
duced into the circuit. The galvanometer is an in-
strument in shape like a compass. The needle which
it carries turns from zero point a certain number
of degrees, according to the strength of any electrio
enrrent passing throngh the instroment. Hence the
motion of the needle from the zero point measures
the strength of the earrent. Let us suppose that the
current, passing through the wire E, is sufficient to
turn the needle from 02 to 50°, Then when a piece
of metal, such as the one mouuted on the membrane,
or indeed any bar of soft iron, is brought close to
the poles of the electro-magnet, or Jaid upon them,
the needle of the galvanometer moves at once, and
indicates a disturbance of the strength of the cur-
rent. When the piece of metal is taken away from
the electro-maguet, the galvanometer again shows
a change in the strength of the current, but its re-
cording needle then moves in an opposite direction.
How is this explained? Well, there are several the-
ories whicli, strange to say, are not partienlarly in-
consistent with each other. The civrent may be
conceived of as doing work, and hence losing
strength, when it has to pull at the piece of metal
resented to the poles; it then has less strength lefi
to show on the galvanometer. Of course the pull is
harder and the expenditure of strength in doing
work is greater the nearer the iron approaches the
poles. The other half of this explanation is not so
gimple. Electricians would say that when the iron
is lifted trom the poles a reverse current is caused by
“induction.” To explain all about “induction”
would require too much of #prce and of patience.
If the reader takes kindiy to the notion that the
strength of the current may be decreased by the
work that it does when it attracts the metallie piece
G, he can perhaps also conceive that wien that piece
of metal 1s removed from the poles a certain portion
of the work done by the experimenter’s arm in re-
moving the metal may be tiansumted into an addi-
tion to the strength of the electric current in the
wire.
WAVES IN A CURRENT,
A very convenient phrase, indeed, is that which
ealls the passage of electricity a“ enrrent,” Bear-
ing in mind that it 1s rather a simile than a fact,
it will serve to picturgto the mind what happens
when the telephone is in operation. Suppose that
the current of electricity is represented by a steady
siream issuing from a pipe, and rnuniuge slong
smoothly. At the point 8 the current strikes a
stone, and is thenceforth thrown into waves, After
this, the enrrent flows overa dam, T. If the dam is
easily shaken, the waves will communicate to it vi-
bration, and those vibrations wiil exactly corre-
spond to the waves, Applying this conception to
the teleplione, the approach of the metal G ocea-
sions waves in the clectric erent, und these are
cominunicated by the current to the vibrating lid D.
In an exceedingly instractive lecture a few nighis
aro on the Grdmme electric light, at Cooper Lusii-
tute, Dr. G. F. Barker made clear Faraday's view
of this subject. ‘There are rays of force extending
in certain well-ascertained curves avound and to
some Gistance from the poles of a macnet, What-
ever contiacts or expands that field of force, creates
a current of electricity, or, where a curvent already
exists, strengthens or weakens it. And this, again,
is the efiect of the approneh of iron to the poles, or
its removal from thew, as Dr. Barker proved to his
audience by the oscillation of a gaivanometer, the
iruage of which was magnified aud tloown on a
screen by electric light, But what act
place in the iron of the magnet around which the
current flows, is a rearrangement of its molecules,
Mr. Joule of England has the ercdit of discovering,
many years ago, that the iron through which
an electric current flows is, elongated dnring the
passage of the cwrent. A series of exact experi
ments by Prof. A. M. Mayer, about five years ago,
developed a large amount of curious data on this
subject. Among other things proved was the fact
that a lengthening oceurs in an iron rod around
which a current is passing and that the increase in
the volume of the rod thus caused, is exactly equaled
by areduction in volume—ashrinkage in the diameter
of the rod. Another point ascertained was that the
change in the dimensions of metal is practically in-
stantaneous the whole change of Jength produced
by a given strength of cleeiricity is equally great
whether the current is turned on very slowly or all
at once. Just so in the operation of the telephone,
the changes in the strength of the current must be
wholly and instantly transmitted, no matter what
may be their number and variety, Furthermore—
and this is a very suggestive experiment—if the
metal G on the membrane is suffered to rest against
the magnetic poles, any sounds sent will still be
heard, though faintly, They are reproduced by the
molecular movements of the iron itself,WHAT THE SPIRITUALIST MEDIUMS MISSED,
In point of fact the last-entioned coutrivanee is
to some extent a reproduction of the earliest tele-
phone, invented by a German--Philip Reiss—about
15 years ago. In that telephone the vibrations of a
stretched membrane in the sending instrument were
cansed to make and break an electric cirenit. The
receiving instrument was a single-coil magnet in-
closing an iron bar, and was mounted on a sounding
box. Music could be transmitted by this telephone,
and further contrivances developed the sounds re-
ceived so that they could be heard in a large hall
But only the sound of the notes—i. e,, the pitch of the
music—was transmitted. The notes were all equal
in strength and quality. A wuch greater success in
sending music by electricity has been latterly
achieved by the telephone of Mr. Elisha Gray of
Chicago. The public has more or less confounded
the performances of this instrument with those of
the one invented by Prof. Bell. Mr. Gray's tele-
phone was shown at the Centennial Exhibition, and
called forth much interest among the men of science
who examined it. Its leading feature is the use of
tuning-forks. A taning-fork may he so introduced
into a telegraphic circuit as to make and break the
circuit. Such a fork, vibrating a certain fixed num-
ber of times per second, according to its special
pitch or musical note, will break and restore the
electric current an equal number of times per
second. Four years ago Mr. Gray made a curious
discovery as to some means by which this intermit-
tent current can be made audible. If the believers
in mesmerism and psychic force had known of
it in time, they might have made much
capital for their theories out of that dis-
covery and the mystery that enshronded the
performance. Mr. Gray had a violin with a silver
plate set in the front of it. If the end of a wire over
which was sent an intermittent current such as has
been described was held in the hand, and the fingers
of the same hand were lightly rubbed over the silver
plate, the note of the tuning-fork at the other end of
the line was reproduced, and could be distinctly
lly takes
heard proceeding from the violin. A yet more curi-
ous result is attained if the violin is made to rotate
horizontally, or if there is substituted for it a re-
volving sounding box the front of which is covered
with a sheet of metal. The fingers of the hand
holding the telegraph wire are to be pressed against
the rotating metallic plate; then the faster the
plate revolves, the louder is the reproduced sound.
It can be easily heard throughout a large hall
There is evidently a limit to the londness of the
sound, as with high speed the operator's fingers will
be too hard rubbed. Why must the human hand
intervene? If jan exhibitor at a spiritual seance
had shown that apparatns in 1873 and asked that
question, the men of science could not have an-
swered him. He could have trinmphantly turned
his revolving fiddle and said with Hamlet—*“Ay!
there's the rub!” But when Mr, Gray took this con-
trivance with him to England and got Prof. Tyn-
dall’s aid in experimenting upon it, another dis-
covery was made which wholly changed the aspect.
It was shown that neither the human hand, nor liv-
ing nerve, nor vitality itself was needful as amedinm
of communication. Prof. Tyndall reproduced the
musical sound when he substituted a piece of salt
pork for the human hand!
THE SOUNDING BOX RECEIVER.
In Gray's, as in Bell's telephone, a continuous enr-
rent from a main battery is required. The Gray
sending instrument is in outward shape a piano of
two octaves. The tune to be transmitted must be
played on the keys of this piano, Each key has its
own tuning fork, and when a key is depressed a part
of the electric current that travels through the main
line is diverted so that it goes through that particu-
lar tuning fork. The mechanism by which the elee-
tric current is thus switched on and off the line
by a touch to a piano key is somewhat complex,
and its details would not be of interest to the
general reader. The receiving instrument is an
clectro-magnet, KK, mounted by one of its coils
and a support, J, upon a sounding box, L. The
prong of a tuning fork, M, approaches very nearly
but does not quite touch one pole of the magnet;
the handle of the fork is connected with the other
pole through the support, J. When the apparatus is
thus arranged, there must of course be a separate
sounding box for every note that the telephone
transmits,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82000205/1888-03-19/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.251,0.003,1.502,1.229,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BIRTH OF THE TELEPHONE
	Tho decision in tho Telcphono cases
was read by Associate Justice Blatchford
in the United States Supremo Court to
day. It comprised n very elaborato ro
viow of all tho Inventions of the telephone
which havo como up to claim priority to
tlio discoveries of Bell and tho suits
which have been conducted in the courts
to set asldo tho Bell patent.Justice Blatchford holds that the law
docs not require nt tho timo application
Is made for a patent that thcro shall have
been obtained a hluh deurcoof perfection;
that tho results may not havo boon
entirely satisfactory at first in order that
tho patent may Issuonnd stand against
tlio assaults of others; that the electrical
undulation clfects set forth by Bell in his
application havo been fully attained, and
that tho vibration Is identical to tbo de
scription. It Is first necessary to describe
tho process, then the apparatus. Thoro
was nothing to show that anyone had in
vented an nnparntus prior to that In
vented by Bell, although vibration
by electricity had boon transmitted
wire prior to 18."l.by
It was left for Bolt to discover tho
principle, nnd this lie adopted and subse
quently perfected. Thcro Is nothing re
Hiring tho operation of instruments be
oro patent Issues. It is tlio practicability
of the process that Is to ho shown.
It is truo that when Dell got his patents
ho thought tho magnetic process best,
but that docs not provent hint
from using tho electrical pro
cess and attaining tho same results.
Bell discovered tho way to attain tho ro
sults wo havo now in transmitting artlcu
lato sounds by electricity.
A lengthy roviow followed respecting
tho investigations by various electricians
about tho timo of tho issuance of Bell's
patent, and tho conclusion was that no
others haye shown that they over thought
of It.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1906-04-22/ed-1/?sp=41&q=THDA+TELEPHONE&st=text&r=0.012,0.725,0.193,0.193,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THIRTIETH BIRTHDAY OF THE TELEPHONE
	fore Dr. Bell had discovered that his
theory of the telephone was practical,
.?nd since that time they had worked
?iight and day to develop Instruments
that would make that discovery useful.
:3?ut still they were far from satisfied;
nnd on this March day, In 1876, they
??vere prepared for further experiments.
Watson was listening at the Instru?
ment In his room. Suddenly, almost un
.'?xpccterily, for It Hcemed almost too
Kniarvelous a thing to be true, he heard
'"Bell's voice. Faintly, yet distinctly,
V these words camo over the wire to him:
j "Mr. Watson, come here. I want you."
That was the first message ever de?
livered by telephone. Though .Informal,
It was decisive. It lifted telephony
high out-of the realm of theory" and ex?
periment into that of practical realities.
Mr. Hell and Mr, Watson first met-in
1874. At that time Mr. Bell was pro Boll one day confided to Watson hit
belief that It was possible to devise
apparatus by means of which the most
e-omplcx sound vibrations, even those
of the human voice, could bo trans
formes! Into electrical vibrations at one
enel of a telegraph wire, transmitted
over the wire, and be changed back at
tho other end of the wire Into the
original sounds without loss of their
most delicate overtoneB. In brief, hin
belief was that a telegraph Instrument
that would talk could be devised.
It was on June 1S75, while they
were, engaged In experimenting with
the multiple or "harmonic" telegraph,
that the accident happened which con?
vinced Bell that his idea\of telephony
was capable of realization. Mr- Bell
was engaged In rctunlng one of the
springs of the receiver In his room, nnd
to ascertain if the pitch was correct he
had pressed It'against his ear and was
listening to tho faint sound of tho lnter
mlttent current passing through the
magnet. All at once the spring of the
receiver In the other room stopped vl
I brating, nnd, to start it, Mr. Watson
snapped It with his linger. With a
shout of excitement Mr. Bell came
rushing out nnd asked what had been
done. Mr. Wal#m explr^ned. "Do It
again," said Bell,, and ,'Jlatson spent
the rest of the day snapping springs.
spring that Mr. "Watson had snapped
had become permanently magnetised by
long use near Its magnet, and conse?
quently was In a condition to generate
by Its vibration the undulatory electric
current which forms the basic principle
of telephony. ho first telephone was, indeed,
rudo affair compared .with tho compni
and convenient apparatus that nowi
days stnnds on the business man's desl
but, appearances aside, It was service
able, The question In tho minds of tli
two young men who were at work poi
fectlng it was how far It coulel enrr
sound. Finally, In October, 1876, tho
decided to mako their first exporlmen
In "long dlstanco" telephony. Provlou
to that time they hnd been tolophonln
only from one rnom to another In thel
I;apartment In Exoter Flaco. Now the:
arranged for tlio use of a private tele
graph lino belonging to tho Walwortl
Manufacturing Company. The line rat
from tho company's office In Boston ti
the factory In Cambrldgeport, a dlstanoi
of about two miles, On tho evening of October Oth Mr. Bel
took olmrge of the Boston station nm
Mr, Watson of the Cambridgeport sta?
tion, and, at a signal given by telegraph.
th|iy connected'their telephones with
tho wlro and began to converse. The;
experiment was entirely successful,
Mr, Watson reports Ihnt on his wny
back to Boston he could senrcoly re?
strain himself from telling the other
passengers in tho car of the unpre?
cedented achievement In which ho had
Just taken part, As for Bell, some Idea
of his feelings may he gleaned from the
fact that whon ho burst Into the labora?
tory at Exeter Pisco ho grasped his as?
sociate by the shoulders, whirled him
around tho room, and exolnimed: "Wat
Bon, this night's work will make mo
famous,"
In May,- 1S77, the first Bell Tolophono
Company Issued circulars announcing
that 1( was ready for business, The
Stockholders wore Mr. Boll., Gardiner
Green Hubharfl (Bell's father-in-law).
Thomas Sanders, of Salem, nnd Mr.
Wntson, There was trouble In the air
over patents, and the prospects were
anything but encouraging. At one time
tho company presented to tho Western
I Union Telegraph Company, which threat?
ened to become Its most formidable op?
ponent, proposition to sell all its pat?
eut?, right and properly for ?Jfio.ooo; but
the telegraph men rejected the propo?
sition and prepared to fight the matter
out In Hie courts.
It was lucky for, the Belt company
thftt the proposition Which It had mada
In ft moment of doubt nnd discourage?
ment was hot accepted, for, though the
ensuing lawsuits were cosily, the result,
In every Instance, was'a Victory for ihn
Poli sido; and thus stimulated. Ihn
telephone company pushed forward lo
developments the like of which the world
has never seen. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069395/1915-02-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Bell+Belle+Telephone+telephone+transcontinental+telephones</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>FIRST TRANSCONTINENTAL TELEPHONE CALL LINKING THE COASTS
	ess than forty years ago Alexan
der Graham Bell, standing in a little
attic at 6 Exeter Place", Boston, sent
through a crude telephone, his own
invention, the first spoken words ev
er carried over a wire and the words
were heard and understood by his
associate, Thomas A. Watson, who
was at tho receiver in an adjacent
room. On that day, March 10, 1876,
the telephone was born, and the
first message went over the only
telephone line in the world a line
less than a hundred feet long. The
world moves a long way ahead in
the span of one man's life. On Mon
day afternoon, January 25, this
same Alexander Graham Bell, sitting
in the offices of the American Tele
phone Telegraph company at New
York, talked to this same Thomas A.
Watson in San Francisco, over-a wire
stretching 3,400 miles across the con
tinent and part of a system that in
cludes 9,000,000 telephones, connect
ed by 21,000,000 miles of wires.
In that same memorable year of
1876 Dom Pedro de Alcantara, em
peror of Brazil, visiting the first tel
ephone exhibition at our first great
national show, the Philadelphia cen
tennial, picked up the receiver, lis
tened as Professor Bell talked at the
other end of the room, and, amazed
at the wonder of the thing, cried
out: "My God, it speaks." Had
Dom Pedro lived to see the Pan
American exposition he could have
heard Professor Bell talking to him,
not merely from the other end of a
room, but from the other side of a
continent.
The Pan-American exposition it
self, planned to celebrate the com
pletion of the Panama canal and the
joining of the Atlantic and Pacific
oceans, will mark a still closer wed
ding of the east and west. When its
gates are thrown open on February
20, San Francisco will not only be
nearer to New York through a short
ening of its water ways, but will be
in constant and instantaneous touch
with it through the medium of
speech. It is a curious fact, too,
that this second great feat of engi
neering, this other canal, this even
more intimate connection between
the two seaboards has been com
pleted in the same year. Quietly,
almost unnoticed, but steadily and
bravely, while the gigantic steam
shovels were cutting their way
through the earth in the' south, the
engineers of sound and electricity
were weaving their magic webs
through the air and pushing on to
ward the Golden Gate. Their work
has been less spectacular, it has ex
cited little attention, but these men
have met obstacles as Hard to over
come as the Culebra slide, and they
have conquered them. The long-dreamed-of
transcontinental lino is
no longer a dream. New York can
talk to San Francisco.
A DATE TO REMEMBER.
Monday, January 25, 19l6, has
taken its place among the momen
tous dates in the annals of science
and human progress. On that day,
in the presence of groups of promi
nent men on either coast, tho trans
continental telephone wires were
given their first public test, and the
completion of the. line was formarly
celebrated. Distinguished men in
the offices of tho Pacific Telephone
and Telegraph company in San Frari
cisco conversed freely with distin
guished men on the Atlantic sea
board, and one more great chapter
in the history of telephony was fin
ished as Bell, sitting in tho offices of
tho American Telephone and Tele
graph company in New York, talked
to Watson across a continent.
There was no hitch in tho pro- The bridge which Van Horn sought
to destroy was not greatly damaged.
gram, or any doubt as to the immed
iate success. Those who talked over
the telephone did not raise their
voices above the usual conversation
al pitch, and the replies came back
from across the continent, clear and
instantaneous. There wa? no more
effort, delay or indistinctness than in
talking across a table. Professor
Bell says that he thought out the
telephone in Salem. A fitting place
for its conception there is witch
craft in it,' and tho most blase of
business men in the offices of the
American Telephone and Telegraph
company on Monday felt something
akin to uncannines3 at tho thought
that his voice had gone across thir
teen states, shot over prairies and
through forests, hurtled through
cities, climbed the Rockies, skimmed
across the desert and reached tho
Pacific coast, and the answer had
come back to him in an eye-wink.</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060127/1926-07-24/ed-1/?sp=5&q=telephone&st=text&r=-0.143,-0.062,1.352,1.352,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>The telephone directory is not merely
a book of numbers, but is a very def
inite part of telephone service. It is
“information” at a glance and is used
millions of times daily. It is not
merely a few pages of paper carry
ing the alphabetical listings with the
telephone numbers of the community
It serves, but it is a necessity to the
business and social life of every sec
tion.The fiftieth anniversary of the In
vention ,of the telephone finds the
United States still undisputed leader
of the world’s telephone progress. We
have in this country 62 per cent of
all the telephones In the world, or
one telephone for every seven people.
With ten times as many telephones in
proportion to population as the rest
of the world, and with 191 telephone
conversations per person in a single
year, the United States maintains hei
talephone leadership which began halt
a century ago when Alexander Gra
ham Bell made hie great invention in
a Boston garret.
New evidence of America’s pre-eml
ence in the telephone field is afforded
by a compilation of telephone statis
tics of the world which has Just been
published. The task of obtaining ac
curate information from remote coun
triei has taken many months, and the
figures therefore reflect conditions as
of January 1, 1925.
On that date there were 26,038,508
telephones In use throughout the
world. Of these, 16,072,758, or over
three-fifths, were in the United States.
Surope had four times as many peo
ple as the United Slates, but less than
half as many telephones. The 6,895,-
366 instruments in Uurope constituted
only 26 per cent of the world’s total
telephones. The remaining 12 per cent
were scattered through all the other
countries and continents outside of the
Unted Slates and Europe. New York
•tate alone had nearly as many tele
phones as Germany and more than the
whole of any other foreign country.
Our American telephone system also
showed a greater net annual growth
than the telephone systems of all the
other countries in the world put to
pother. The increase in number of
telephones in the United States during
1924 was 839,407, while in all for
eign countries combined it was only
160,268.
Not only in total telephones and in
telephone growth, but also in number
of telephones per 100 population, the
United States was easily first. We
had 14.2 telephones for every 100 peo
ple in this country; Canada had 11.6,
Denmark 9.0, New Zealand 8.7, Sweden
6.9, and Norway 6.1. In Germany
there were but 3.9 telephones per 100
inhabitants, in Great Britain and
Northern Ireland 2.8, and In France
1.7. It may be noted in passing that
the telephone systems of these three
countries were under government own
ership and operation. Of the world’s
lotal telephones, oaly 29 per cent were
ander public ownership, the remainThis is done not so much for tha
value of the old books as junk paper,
as to get them out of the way, so that
telephone users will consult the latest
issue in making calls. There are al
ways a large number of new listings
in the latest telephone directory, and
in addition, there are thousands of
miscellaneous changes in every issue.
While the delivery of the telephone
directory lg usually made In a reason
ably short length of time, this does
not mean that the work of getting out
the book is over until the next one is
off the press. A large force of clerks
is employed continuously In the prep
aration of “copy" for the new issue,
which will be delivered about six
months after the present one has been
placed in the home or office.
population in the United States were
served by 11.6 telephones per 100 peo
ple, a record equalled in no other
country. In Canada these smaller com
munities had 9.8 telephones per 100
population, in Denmark 7.1, and in
New Zealand 8.8. The larger Eu
ropean countries were far behind in
this reßpeot, with farmers' telephone
lines almost unknown. There were
only 8.4 telephones per 100 inhabitants
in communities of under 100,000 popu
lation in Germany, 1.7 in Great Britain
and Northern Ireland, and 1.0 in
France. British and French telephone
development, in fact, was concentrated
principally In the larger cities. In
each oase over one-third of all the na
tion's telephones were in its capital
city. Even so, London with 5.9 tele
phones per 100 people, and Paris with
7.6, were far surpassed by Washing
ton, D. C., whleh had 25.8 telephoner
per 100 inhabitants,- by Omaha, which
had 28.5, and by San Franclsoo, which
had 29.9. Stockholm, with 24.8 tele
phones per 100 people, alone among
foreign cities had attained a telephone
development commensurate with that
of United States cities.
In use of the telephone, Americans
averaged 191 telephone conversations
per inhabitant during 1924, while in
Denmark the number of conversations
per person was I*l, in Norway 113,
and in Sweden 106. The Germans used
the telephone only to the extent of an
average of 30 conversations per person
during that year, while the taciturn
British contented themselves with an
average of but 23 conversations per
inhabitant, or less than one-eighth as
many as we Americans.
SMALL UNITS MAKS UP
TELEPHONE BUSINESS
When a customer drops a nickel into
the slot of a coin box telephone and
gives the operator a number the tele
phone company is selling five cents’
worth of service. It is a small retail
transaction. Yet the whole business
of all the telephone companies of the
country is made up of retail trans
actions.
Of course, some sales are larger
than others; long-distance calls nec
essarily cost more than five cents.
But every telephone call whether
local or long-distance, is a separate
sale. It is the sale of a connection
between a particular pair of tele
phones. Every connection is "made
to order.” Every order for a particu
lar connection is handled separately.
Retailing, according to the diction
ary, Is “selling in small quantities,
1 selling directly to the consumer.” That
1 is Just what the telephone companies
do. They sell tepehone calls in small
quantit es tone at a time), directly to
the con> .inner. The telephone business
Is a retail business.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016209/1946-12-26/ed-1/?sp=3&q=telephone&r=-0.362,-0.071,1.724,1.41,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1952-12-06/ed-1/?sp=10&q=telephone&st=text&r=-0.191,-0.069,1.382,1.382,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Bel! then rigged up a thin metal
disc, or diaphragm, so that the
voice of the speaker would set the
air molecules behind it into motion.
He used an electromagnet so
that the vibrations of the disc
would start an electric current
flowing in the circuit and pull the
disc in the receiver back and forth
to reproduce the sound.
The modern telephone of today
utilizes the same principle, but
a chamber filled with carbon
granules the roasted coal
gives the better type of trans
mitter and receiver the best use
of the electrical current.
So voice waves push intermittent
ly against the transmitter dia
phragms and speed to the called
telephone over telephone wires
where they push at the receiver
disc in the same way. Then the
waves push at your eardrum in
the same sequence and frequency
they came from the throat of the
caller.
That’s what happens by using
a little roasted coal and some
electric current. It’s easy when
you know how, telephone people
say.rom one telephone to almost
39 million Bell telephones in 77
years this astounding growth tells
only a fragment of a great story
of service. Better than anything
else, the telephones meets our
need to communicate quickly with
other people in other places.
Throughout the telephone’s brief
history, in peace and war, Bell
System men and women have
striven constantly to make it ever
more useful and valuable to more
people. They have been able to
build so well in such a short time
because the people of America
have given them the resources, the
encouragement and the responsi
bility they needed to do the job.
Asa result, th® telephone has
helped immeasurably to make
America's production capacity
and her standard of living second
to none. The telephone will oro
.vide even greater service to the
nation in the years ahaad.
One evening, in a top-floor bed
room of a boarding bouse in Bos
ton; Alexander Graham Bell was
trying out a new liquid telephone
transmitter. It was connected by
wire to a receiver in another room
down the hall. At the receiver was
Thomas Watson, Bell’s assistant.
While Bell had earlier proved that
speech sounds could be transmitted
electrically, his first telephone had
not been able to carry an intelli
gible sentence. This first sentence carried by
telephone was spoken on March
10, 1876. It rewarded years of
thought and experimentation, of
ever-present hope yet painfully
slow progress. Anew and wonder
ful means of communication had
been born. Mr. Bell never thought of his
telephone as just another mechani
cal invention to be sold and for
gotten. To him it was an instru- If the telephone was to fulfill
its destiny, some means of inter
connection had to be found so that
any telephone could be connected
quickly with any other.One of the best indications
a city’s economic and population
growth is its volume of both local
and long distance telephone call.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045188/1907-09-03/ed-1/?sp=8&q=telephone&st=text&r=-0.328,-0.033,1.692,1.384,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89060127/1923-07-28/ed-1/?sp=7&q=telephone&r=-0.355,-0.07,1.71,1.399,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-ping-pong-craze</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1900-12-23/ed-1/?sp=29&q=TABLE+TENNIS&st=text&r=-0.417,0,1.834,1.5,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>TABLE TENNIS
	able tennis is the name of a new game which
was introduced in England a short time ago.
and has already become one of the most popu
lar of indoor amusements. It is the came
of lawn tennis in miniature, played on an or
dinary dining table. The net is a tiny one, made
of gauxe stretched between two uprights, which
rest on a bar laid across the table. The balls
are made of the thinnest kind of pyroxyline ma
terial, and are consequently very light. The
racquet has a slender handle and a blade with
a frame about one-half inch thick, which Is cov
ered on both sides with thin drumhead Material.
The play and counting are practically the satnas in lawn tennis, but, according to the rules,
'•the player serving must not put his racquet
over the table nor have it above his wrist." That
is, he must serve underhand and never over
hand, but after service he may hit the ball as he
likes, but he most not volley.
The contact of the light ball with the drum
head racquet produces a pleasant sound, and
because of this sound th(» game received the
name "pompom."
Among the rules for playing the game are the
following:
No faults are allowed: if a fault is served.
that is, the ball does not go over the net or goes
off the table without touching the opposite side
to the server, a |M>int is counted to the non
server.
If the net is touched by the l»all. and the ball
goes over, and otherwise the service is correct,
it is a let. and counU nothing to either side.
If a volley is taken a point is counted against
the person</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1902-01-05/ed-1/?sp=26&q=PING-PONG&st=text&r=-0.467,0,1.839,1.504,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING-PONG
	The three men who occupied the studio flat
were having their quiet end-afternoon srnoks
together. There was the artist, w hose hair haj
turned gray after long years of painting an*
black and white doings; the youth who, fcesi
from art school, was just making a start, and
the man of business, who was the saving clause
of the combination. He put up the money wh»3
black and whites would not sell and the youths
checks from home were delayed In the mails.
"I wish people would find something new wia
which to entertain us, said the man of buij.
ness, in a bored tone.
"New Year is coming," chirped the youth, aa
obvious statement, setir.g that Christmas «xj
just one day past. "Perhaps Santa Claus tLpgti
off' the dear girls to a new game."
There*! nothing new under the sun. Billy*
said the •Id artist. "If taert was I'd draw it jj
hurry."
Then there came a knock on the door, and a
messenger appeared with a dainty note. Billy
grasped it hastily. Billy was in love.
"It's addressed to all of us," he said, with di*.
appointment.
"All the more reason you should hurry up aaj
lead it,"' commanded the man of business.
"It's from Harriet," he murmured, as he read
it to himself.
"Head out loud, uli>.t"" commanded one of the
older men.
"Won't you ccme up to-morrow night and
play ping-pong." read Billy. "Now, what is
ping-pong?"
"Search me?" remarked the one who was nut
artistic, except when it came to making money.
"Sounds Chinese," said the artist.
"I've heard of 'pom-pom,' remarked BiUy.
"That's a sort of big gun which makes a funny
noise." Billy had ence had the idea of beeoininj
a military man. "But ping-pon^r— that's a new
one on me."
"Some new style of bridge. I suppose." mut
tered the artist. "It's not for me. I've sacri
ficed enough on that altar."
"Well. I'm going up to play ping-pong," an
nounced the youth. "I don't care what it is, tit
name's new. Better come along. Jack. You
were growling a minute ago about there being
nothing new, and here you are."
Dilly went to Harriet's and played ping-pong,
and when he had not retumeO by midnight th«
other fellows knew that he was enjoying it. H«
would not tell them what the new game was
when he finally put in an appearance, but ad
vised them to find out for themselves.
An indoor edition of tennis is ping-pong, til*
name coming from the curious sound which tie
parchment rackets give forth when they striis
the little balls. It is played on the dining room
taMe, across the centre of which a low net is
stretched. Th> rules are almost the same as
in tennis, and the points are counted tennis
fashion. There is even mure chance for skilful
handling of the ball than In outduor game*
and there are tricks innumerable which add
interest and variety. Skilful players can ii??
up the volleying process until interest reaches
fever pitch. It is almost as exciting for tie
spectators as for the players, which U core
than can be said of tennis.
It is an absorbing game, as the EngHsh S«l
tell you. It his been played i:i London ilisisj
romis for the last two or three years; but ha
never been strictly in vogue until this winter
The ollieers of the British army carried pir.g
peng sets to South Africa with t'.u-m. and have
set up their tab) on tho wldt when the Ecea
let them remain Ln camp long enough.
Why the game has not taken hold in tiia
country is something which Americans who live
In London cannot understand. They have writ
ten home about the beauties and delisht3 o! v
ping-pong. They laud it to the skies for tie
exercise it affords to busy c.tn who have o
work in offices all day. and to women who
occupied with a round of teas a^d recepucsi
PING-PONG.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86071197/1902-03-02/ed-1/?sp=3&q=fad+table+tennis&st=text&r=0.13,0.5,0.209,0.171,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE ALL-ABSORBING FAD
	Warming tho battledores slightly before
tho tiro will lmptovo their elasticity but
caic must be taken not to overheat them
When wlogs are used wlb the net these
should bo died up on the posts so that
they project out beyond the edge Of the
table aaid thus prevent n ball being re
turned tound the sides of the posts Instead
of over the net
1 The game Is for two players They
shall stand one at each end of the tabic
The plajer who lirst delivers tho ball shal
i e called tho server and the other the
sttikorout
2 At the end of tie first game tho
strlkorout shall become tho server and the
sirvei shall become the strikerout una
so on alternately
a The service shall bo strictly under
hand und delivered from beyond tha end
of the table
4 The ball served must drop anywhere
ou the table top beyond the net and Is then
In play If It drops Into the net or off the
tabie It counts to the striker out There is
no second son lie as In lawn tennis
0 In fretting It Is a let If the ball touch
the net lu parsing over
0 If the ball in play htrllscg any obiect
above or around the table beloro it bounces
on tho table top Itself net or post except
ed It counts against the player
7 The berver wins a stioku If the strlker
out fulls to return the service or return
the service or ball In play off the table
b The strikerout wins n stroke If the
server bcrve a fault or falls to return the
ball In play or return the ball In play so
that It falls off the table
0 No volleyllng Is allowed hut as long
as the ball touches the table top It Is In
play aud can be taken at half volley
10 On either player winning his rtrst
stroke the score is called 15 for that
plajer on either player winning his sec
ond stroke the score Is called SO for that
player on either plajer winning his third
stroke the score is called 40 for that play
er and tha toiuth stroke won by either
player Is scoied game for that player ex
es pt as below
11 If both players have w n three
stiokes 40 all the score Is called deuce
snd the next stroke won by either player is
scored advantage to thit player If tho
same player wl the nest stroke he win
the game If hi loses the next stroke the
store is again called deuce and so on
until either player wins the two strokes lm
mediately following the score of deuce
when the game is scored for that player
12 The player who flist wins six games
wins a set
13 The game may nlso be scored by
points twentytwo up The players lu this
cn e change the service aucr every tive
points scoied like overs at cricket
The apparatus of the game costs about
260 i
A pingpong dance In which the women
wear pingpong patches and powdeted hair
Is the latest development of the present
mania Tho women carrying white balls
with a red number on each and each gen
tleman a scarlet ball with a corresponding
fluro in white walk down the ball room
and meet at a silken net Batting begins
Af soon as each dancer secures the ball the
numbers are called out pairing oft begins
and the couples glide down the room hand
in hand in minuet style The latest rival
of pingpong bv the wnv Is table bowls
which has Just been exhibited at the Alex
andra palace</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-04-06/ed-1/?sp=23&q=ping-pong+table+tennis&st=text&r=-0.272,-0.077,1.544,1.544,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING-PONG
	i'iiiK pong is Bimply modified tennis
played upon a ta-ble in the houft« instead
of a court in the open air and is, in fact,
table tennis. Bui when the little celluloid
ball strikes the hard surface of a table
the contact prodapes a sound best
d scribed by the word "ping" and as it
bounds against the viium racquet the
Bound "pong," a full note lower, issues.
Some person with a quick ear and a
quicker imagination translated these
sounds and the gamfe was christened with
the catchy name "ping pong," a name
tnat has helped to call attention to it.
The balls are very light, much like blown
birds' iggs to the touch, and there is no
possibility of their breaking or of injur
ing anything they may strike except, of i
course, fragile bric-a-brac. The racquets
are light rattan affairs, covered with
vellum. In this respect they differ from j
those used in ordinary tennis, although
ih>- dealers are showing some specially
constructed ones strung with catgut, as j
are tennis racquets. They were ordered
by ]>ing pong players' who are also tenn:s
experts and who believe they can play
In tter with the strung racquets than with
the vellunf-covered ones. Any table
about the height of a billiard table and
jn the neighborhood o. nine feet long by
five feet wide will do for the game. Many
use dining tables. To be correct one
should have a table, the surface of which
has been painted dark green, or covered
With biliard cloth, it makes no difference
in the game whether it is played with or
Without a cloth upon the table. Without
a cloth the balls will, of course, bounce
higher. The game is played by two or
Jour persons, usually by two. For the
at in which thfe are two players,
and this is the game in high favor, each
player stands art one end of th<- table.
The one first delivering the ball is called
the "serve;;" t):.- other person is th-e
".■strikeout." At the end of the iirst game
the "strikeout"-becomes the "server' and'
00 on alternately to the end of the sets.
As soon as theball is served and drops
nnywlK re on the table top beyond the t.et
it is 'play." if it drops Into the net-or
off the table it counts to the "strike out."
I ie is no second service as in lawn ten
jus. On either player winning the first
strike, the score is called fifteen for that
fourth stroke won by either player is sac
ond "game," unless both players have
yon three strikes, "forty all," whsn the
scon- is called deuce, and the next stroke
v.on by either player is scored "advan
tage" to that player.
[f the same player wins the next stroke
the game Is his: If he loses the next
eiroke the score is again deuce, and so i
on until either player wins the two
Strokes imediately following the score
player; on either player winning his or
her second stroke, the score for that play
er is thiity. On either player winning- the
third stroke, the score is forty, and the
of deuce, and the "game" is scored for
that player. The player who lirst wins
six games wins the set. In tourna
ments usually three sets are played by
each <.im;)etitor against each other one.
The rules for playing are similar to
those in lawn teunis, except that no over
hnnd service is allowed. There are no
urts marked as in lawn tennis, the
~"\i of the table forming the court, so
that the ball striking any part of the ta
ble is in play. The strokes, apart from
the service, are divided into two main
lasses—the half volley and all other
Etrokee. The half volley is when the bull table. The player hits where he thinks
the ball will be, not at the ball itself,
and it is, therefore, almost impossible
to actually hit is half voiieyin^. Ji is the
ball which hits the racket, and not the
racket that hits the ball. This ia en
tirely defensive play. To attack, the
ball must be struck after it has reached
the top of the bound, or even later, for on
ly then has the player complete control of
the ball. When the ball bounds high it
may be smashed straight on the table,
but if your opponent gets back so as to
make the return, twist your wrist BO that
the ball is hit at right angles to the
flight or even somewhat underneath; it
will drop close to the net and come
straight up or even bounce back over the
net. An effective stroke in reply to a
hard (irive is that called the "crouch
smash." As the ball cornea toward you,
crouch down and hit It at the edge of the
table. This is a good return for a hard
service, but it is most difficult to ac
complish. All these strokes can be done
■backhanded— -in fact, some are such
easier, as, owing to the wrist having
more play in the proper direction, a (,-rtat
er twist can be imparted to the ball.
In addition a ball falling on the right
hand side»f the table can be driven with
the back of the hand in any d-esircu di
rection. This stroke should only Le used
when pressed by a hird ball.
It will be gathered from th<^ strokes
described that play can be made both
back and forehand. This gives many
more opportunities for deceiving an op
ponent. Variety is the secret of success.
Nev r let your opponent anticipate your
intention. When driven to swing, after
hitting the ball, do not stop and turn
back, but continue the swing the same
way, bo as to make a complete circle.
The player i an get square with the table
much quicker by doing this. Ping pong
sets may be had to suit any fancy or any Ping pong- balls are largely im
ported, although American manufactur
ers are experimenting with various mate
rials in hope of improving the celluloid
spheres now in use, giving the regula
tion s|ze and weight. The net is usually
hand-made, of from five to seven inches
In height, linen bound, with a fair de
gree of elasticity. The poles on which it
is stretched are shapely wooden pegs,
with leather bottoms, which protect the
table, to which they are fastened with
clamps. In each outfit there are usually
a half dozen bats or battledores and one
dozen balls. Whether the game Is to
have permanent place among the amuse
ments is a question that i being discuss
ed by those who have watched and ana.
lyzed the rise and fall of fads in the way
of indoor and outdoor amusements. Its
champions_ contend that it has every pos
sible requisite for the proper exercise of
body and mind that young women who
are noj equal to the roughing and phys
ical strain entailf-d by golf, tennis and
kindred strenuous sports will be heartily
and healthfully benefited by ping pong.
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016357/1902-05-03/ed-1/?sp=7&q=PING-PONG+ping+pong+craze&st=text&r=0.193,0.661,0.207,0.169,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING-PONG IS A CRAZE
	If youre writing about the thepingpong theplngl1011g theping
pingpong ping pong craze you cant make it t too toostrong oo oostrong oostrong
strong So far as I know we havent haventsold haventsold haventsold
sold a set to any old ladles la les home yet yetbut yetbut yetbut
but I dare are say the game will reach reachthem reachthem reachthem
them in time This craze beats any anything anything anything
thing I ever heard of Our belief is isthat Isthat Isthat
that its only beginning Hot weather weathermay weathermay weathermay
may affect our sales somewhat but butwo butwe
wo look for an increased demand next nextfall nextfall nextfall Our indoor putting green In the theback theback theback
back of the th store has been occupied by bya bya
a pingpong ping poug table for several weeks weeksLfits weeksL weeksLets
Lets L ts of people who never saw the thegame thegame thegame
game come In here and watch a few fewsets fewsets fewsets
sets get fascinated by the play and nndcud riudend andend
end by buying racquets and balls anda and anda anda
a net to take home and set up on their theirdiningroom theIrdlnlngroom theirdining
diningroom dining room or billiard table Theres Theresa
a game going on here almost every everyhour ceryhOUl everyhour
hour of the day People cant seem to toget toget toget
get enough of IL ILThe It ItTho ItTho
Tho clubs have been and are still stilltlys stillt10 stilltl
tlys t10 tl o stronghold of the craze although althoughthe nlthouhtho althoughthe
the newspapers have had more to say sayabout sayabout sayabout
about the play In brokers ofllces of lces and andon andon andon
on ocean steamers So sudden has been beenthe beenthe beenthe
the passion for the sport and so much muchroom muchroom muchrOonl
room does a regulation table take up upthat upthat upthat
that most of the clubs have had to togive togive togive
give up some other sport in whole or orI hough he may begin by scoffing at atthe atthe atthe
the childs play ends in becoming becomingcither becomIngeither becomingeither
either an enthusiast entllUslastor or a disappointed disappointedbut lsappolnledbut
but persistent duffer dufferCollege dufferCollega dufferCollege
College clubs or other clubs fre frequented tree treequented frequented
quented by younger men are the worst worstsufferers worstsufferers worstsufferers
sufferers from the pingpong ping pong malady maladyTho maladylo maladyI1he
I1he Tho lo Harvard 1 alvald Club early In Inthcwlutol Inthcwlutolput the winter winterput winterputn</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016353/1902-05-11/ed-1/?sp=2&q=table+tennis&st=text&r=0.379,0.182,0.227,0.186,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>MAKING A PING-PONG SET AT HOME
	Of all the Indoor games that the wrl wrlr wrlcr wrier
cr r bas tried trIedand and bo has tackled about aboutill aboutn aboutill
ill n of them themnont none has proved such Jolly follyIQod Jollyood jollyfCod
fCod ood fun as table tennis or as the Engish Eng EngIsh
Ish call It pingpong F1rst i First irstas as Si to the tb r rackets clictS In England Englandlie England1te
lie kind most favored have centres of oflarchment ofnrchment oflarchment
larchment like a drumhead from fromVhlch fromvhlch fromwhich
Vhlch the ball rebounds with that bum bumfling humnlng humg
fling pingpong ping pong sound which gives the thefame therame thelame
fame Its name nameThe nampThe nameThe
The writer prefers the string racket racketPieces Jacketrleces racket4leeos
Pieces of rattan soaked sOI1I Ctl a while In Inrteamlng inrteamlng inrteaming
rteamlng hot water WI1 tar to make them very verytupplo verytupple verytupelo
tupelo make good racket frames A Arooden Aooden Awoden
rooden handle hollowed out at the end endvlth endrith endvltb
vlth grooves for the rattan frame to toIt toIt toIt
It In Is simply constructed us shown shownn
n the thedlagram diagram above In stringing the thertrlng thertrlng theitring
rtrlng used on a banjo would be about about1ght aboutofght aboutfight
fight Two strings for each racket racketJiould racketJlOuld rackethould
Jiould b bt enough enoughThese enougllhese enoughThese
These hese strings should shoul bo thoroughly thoroughlylooked thoroughlyoOaked thoroughlycaked
looked and then used while still wet wetDo weto
Do 0 not string too tight for If you do dovhen dorhen dovllen
vhen the strings dry and shrink they theyvlll theym theyvlll
vlll m pull the frame all allout out of shape shapeString shflpeHdng shapetring
String first across and andAlen toen en up and andlown andlawn andtown
lawn exactly as In a regulfClon regul on racket racketn
n making n support for your net a aouple aDuple aduple
Duple of yards of heavy hen telegraph wire wirevlll wirem wirevlll
vlll m answer Take each length and andlouble alldIiouble andlouble
louble and bend into shape shown In Inhe Inbe inbe
be diagram This of Itself may not be belulte beluite beluite
luite stanch enough to hold the net netaut netlut netnut
nut but by running a cord from the thex theop theop
x op p of one wire support down and un unler unler unler
ler the tab table I to the top of the other otherlupport otherIUpport othersupport
support you OU should be able to obtain obtainlie obtainhe obtainhe
he necessary amount of rigidity The Thelet Thelet Thelet
let itself should be about sis Inches InchesUgh Inches11gh inchessigh
Ugh from the table and should clear clearhe clealhe clearhe
he table by enough to allow the ball ballo ballto
o pass easily asllr under it Any material materialvlll materialIVJIl materialgrill
vlll do for the net though a gauze or orlotting orlotting ortotting
lotting of some kind bound at the top topvlth toppith
pith Ith an Inch or two of white tape isLest Is Isest iscst
Lest est As to the table Itself It should
be e simply a smooth and flat surface surfaceibout surfacelbout surfaceibout
ibout five by ten feet or say four by bysight byIght byIght
Ight fret fretThe ftetThe feetThe
The game Is played exactly as tenass ten tensis tenIlls
sis is played except e cept that there is but butne butme butlne
me ne court on either efth el side of the net If Ifthe Ifhe Ifthe
the he ball strikes the very edge e ge of the thetable thel1ble theable
table and 10 o bounces off at In such suel1l1 a way waythat wayat waythat
that at a return la Impossoble call it an anedger anedger anedger
edger and serve over again againThe a Ialn IalnTIle aln alnThe
The method oC scoring is the same lameHil sameis
18 in tennis One rule of the old game gamevhlch gamejhlch gamewhich
which IB barred because of the narrow narrowbounds narrowoundl narrowbounds
bounds ic volleying A ball can never neverie neerJe neverbe
ie returned except on the bounce bouncePickups bouncePlckuPI bouncePickups
Pickups however loWerer are allowable An Another Anther An9ther
other ther strict ruling of pingpong ping pong is that thatQO thatno
QO overhand strokes are allowed the thehand thehand theband
hand must never be raised above the theheight theheIght theheight
height of th tlll elbow Also the serve servemutt 5118I servemust
mutt be delivered from a a point beyond beyondthe beyondthe beyondthe
I the end of the table tableThe tableThe tableThe
The tennis experts and allround nll ronnd ath athletes dhbave athletes
letes have devised It new sort of racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
that makes of tills parlor game nme a rath rathir ratbar rathar
ar strenuous and exciting affair affairThe affairThe affairThe
The racket is simply a l wooden pad paddle pRal11e padale
ale of about the same outside dimen dimensions dim dimenslona en en3lonl
sions as a the pingpong plag pong strung racket racketthat lacketthat racketthat
that is about six inches In diameter diameterroughly dlameterroughly diameterroughly
roughly speaking IIpealtingthe the handle being of ofany oflny ofany
any desired length lengthThe lengUIThe lengthThe
The paddle part IB not of one piece piecewith piecewith piecewith
with the handle hl1n le as it would break or orsplit 01split orsplit
split too easily The handle Is spliced splicedon
on The paddle padaJeon on one side or both bothaccording botIllccordlng bothaccording
according to bow you play is covered coveredwith coveredwith coveredwith
with emery cloth or paper guled on oncarefully oncarefullJ oncarefully
carefully With this thl rough surface surfaceyou lurfacerou surfaceyou
you can cut the ball or give the Law Lawford L LfortI Lawford
ford stroke In splendid fashion fashionAs rub fashionAs Ion IonAs
As to balls the best art those made madeof madeof madeof
of celluloid which can be e bought at atany atn atany
any n sporting or toy store for a few fewcents reweents fewcents
cents apiece apieceThis apleCeTIIIIIJ apieceThis
This pingpong ping pong is I really a great game gameand gameand gameand
and the writer thinks thInk it has 1111 come to tostnyDetroit totarDetrolt tostayDetroit
stnyDetroit Free litre Press PressTli Prfl PrflTIle PressThe
Tli TIle Fever FeverAn lfeverAn FeverAn
An Atchison girl who got 60 50 60month a amonth amonth
month and bad an easy time of Jt Jtcaught Jtcaught itcaught
caught the fever fe rer two years ear ago 0 and andchased andcl1ued andchase
chased a man She had an athletic athletictraining athletletraining t1l1tl t1l1tltraining
training soon caught up with him himand himand himand
and lauded him Now she he does doe all her htrowti herown herawn
own housework including washing and andironing andIroning I
ironing has twin babies and gets her herboard h hfboard i iboard
board and clothes etot Her name should shouldb shouldbe i iIHt
b IHt furnished ill women seised with withthis withthll withthis</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-05-18/ed-1/?sp=46&q=PING+PONG+ping+pong+ping-pong</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SUMMER DELIGHTS OF PING-PONG
	Who plays ping-pong? The answer is
easy: Kverybody. The popularity- of tho
gamo has increased so much in tho last
few months that it has become necessary
to manufacture the racquets and balls in
St. Louis; tho foreign markets are unablo
to furnish even half of what Is required
It is not only a fad, but has undoubtedly
como to stay as much as tennis did years
ago
Tennis is still a popular game. We have
champions; national and local. So It will
bo with ping-pong before another year has
rolled around. Already In St Louis me
have tournaments, championships and
prizes at ping-pong parties. There is great
rivalry between clubs and between mem
bers of clubs. One cannot go to dine now
adays without having to tako part in a
gamo of ping-pong after the dinner. It Is
everywhere and all-absorbing.
Not only men of leisure and ladies of
quality aro indulging In it, hut business
men and college stoudents and women
mho have to busy themselves about a hun
dred and one things during the day. Hv-
erybody has the fever. A ping-pong parlor
on Locust street is crowded every day for
several hours with players and there Is no
sign of any loss of Interest In the game.
Bankers and brokers find that the gamo
gives them moro and better exercise in a
short time that they have been able to get
in any other way. Among the devotees of
the game are Allen West, Dwight Davis,
Harold Kauffman, Hunt Turner and Jim
Drummond. They frequently find tlmo to
meet during the day for a game. Usually
it Is for but a short time, but occaslonaily
they become so Interested that tfcey finish
the afternoon at the table.
But the season for ping-pong Is after
dinner. Then at private residences and at
the clubs there is Invariably a game In
progress. Special rooms have been fitted up
in houses large enough to accommodate
them, and In the clubhouses where the par
ticularly ardent worshippers at tho shrine
of the celluloid ball and the racquet may
commune with their own kind.
Stuart Stlckney, he of golf fame, is a
"fiend" at ping-pong. He says himself that
he has to struggle to keep away from a table
during tho day In order that he may devote
himself to business. But at night and on
Saturdays he gives may to th desire and
Instead of playing golf he stands at a ping
pong table until he is about ready to drop.
The exercise In the game will be ac
knowledged when It Is known that a tennis
and a golf champion have almost forsaken
their favorite game for the enticing ping
pong. Dwight Davis does not play tennis
as much as he used to; and Stuart Stlckney
is rarely seen with his clubs Yet. both ex
celled in their special branches of athletic.
But ping-pong is a winter game, said one
who was only half converted. Needless to
say he could play only fairly. A host rose
to contradict him. Already many lawns are
being prepared for a table during the um
mer. All that is necesasry 1 an even place I
for the table and light enough so that the'
balls may be seen In the evening. In Japan 1
and in England the game Is played the year
'round. Why not In St. Louis?
Evening ping-pong parties during the
summer are already assured. It Is not dis Ralph and Walter McKittrlck, Arthua
Shepley and Dan KIrby- are among the best
and most enthusiastic players In the city.
The Country Club and tho Florissant Club
are utterly crazed over tho game. At pres
ent It holds the trumps over all other
games, and from Indications it will be tha
popular game of the summer at both clubs.
Of course, this does not mean that tenn!
and golf and polo will not havo their de
votees, but ping-pong will bo tho most frequently-
played gamo of tho season.
The women of the city are us enthusias
tic .as the men-possibly more so. and they
havo their claims upon the attention of tho
men and their sports. Ping-pong looks and
sounds llko a game that does not requira
as much cndtiranco and strength as other11
spons anu tint is sid to bo tho reuson
that the women have taken It up. As t,
matter ot fact. It is as violent as nlmnst
any gamo th it Is popular with many peo
ple, but It seems so playful that tho weaker
be. have seized upon It.
It is a fact that one business man of this
c ty a man or more than usual corpulence-
has reduced his weight by forty pounds
playing ping-pong. And If the truth mi.ro
known, it is probably true tint several
women have been enabled to become mora
sylph-like through the medium of the game.
But that Is .v matter concerning which
women will not talk.
Women who are onenlv .anient nl.-ners
of
ny
ping-pong are rot the ones of whom any
one can say they play to reduce thel
weight</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1902-05-25/ed-1/?sp=21&q=daft+ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.056,-313.749,1.111,628.889,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DAFT ON PING-PONG
	Nor are the enthusiasts of the new
gam" to be found only among the fairer
sex, Washington masculinity has given
itself to ping-pong with an abandon
,Nor ar^ the enthusiasts .of the now
which would furnish a profitable study to
the seeker- of pysehologieal phenomena.
Staid congressmen, dignified senators.
Learned members of the bench and bar
When they meet together nowadays dis
cuss not, the political significance of the
lim.s. but the latest-make of ping-pong
racquet.
This -may be regarded as gross exagger
ation. It is a potent fact, however, that
ping p has attained a surprising vogue
■among Washington's public men.
All the leading hotels and cafes are
hastening to open up ping-pong parlors
on their premises, so that their distin
guished patrons may indulge .to their
heart's content in the game.
Senator Maur.a. when asked the other'
■day whether he favored the. erection of aj
ping-pong parlor in the national capital,
l>uckercd up.his brow* and gave the mat
tor a few minutes' serious consideration
before discussing the idea with a smile.
Congressman Sulzer, when asked to ex
plain the tremendous hold that ping-pong
has taken upon members of the-house,
said that it is a wonderful game for~ex
erclse. and gives one a good hand to
sustain the handshaking proclivities of
the vast army of well meaning citizens
who swoop down upon unwilling repre
sentatives of the people with all the re
lentless energy of the notorious New
Jersey musquito upon its helpless victim.
As may be supposed, the stores have
not been slow to take advantage of the
commercial possibilities of the craze. In
-addition to the fact that some of the
larger dry goods emporiums are opening
up ping-pong saloons for the accommo
dation of their patrons, the new game
has an important bearing upon the latest
styles. The ping-pong waist is prom
inently- displayed in the shop windows,
find is a phenomenal seller; while the
new forms of neckwear for women and
men bear handsomely embroidered figure.*
■of ping-pong racquets and balls upon
their silken folds.
Doom of the Tight Corset.
One important reform the game prom,
ises to effect, which may render rational,
the development which has been lavished'
upon it by England and America and im
mortalize the new game as one of the
most valuable and beneficent reform fac
tors of the century.
Ping-pong may abolish the tight laced
■corset.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1902-06-01/ed-1/?sp=13&q=PING-PONG&st=text&r=0.562,-0.001,0.619,0.507,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>THE PING-PONG STRAIN ON THE EYE MUSCLES
	"I have heard much of the ping-pong
ankle, but as the ankle is used compara
tively little in playing I do not think that
the maiaUy is one.v/hich the player need
count. Some players find that the dorsal
muscles arc easily tired, and the man
who stoops a great deal in his effort to
find the balls which have been knocked to
the carpet is lijtcly to suffer from sore
ness and inflammation of the muscles
alrout the pftins. There is in my opinion
j. ping-pong eye, although I deny that
there is si ping-pong face.
"It has been said that the muscles of
the legs and arms are often wearied By
the game. This .is true in a. sense, but I
think that the eye and the brain -will be
exhausted :n ping-pong long before the
muscles used in sending and returning
balls can be affected to any appreciable
extent."
ISEASES with strange names have
Dloliowtd in the wake of ping-pong,
J.ut the real pang is not a fanciful
une. for the watching of the cellu
loid* sphere really strains the eyes.
Let London surgeons talk as they will
about tei.dosyr.ovitis "and p^ig-ponS an
kles: all these are as nothing compared
to tho'strair.ed muscles of the eye of the
Ail ping-pong devotees, even experts,
suffer from the ping-pong eye more or
Jess. Other muscles employed to playing
th* game are ""speedily co-ordinated. To
develop a proper technique is^ing-pong
is no easy matter, and in the endeavor
the eye suffers the most.
There is a ping-pong wrist, of course,
and a ping-pong back, but the player who
can return a ball a hundred times or so
suffers comparatively little from these.
The tyro who bends often to pick up the
balls -which bound upon the carpet is the
one who is most likely to complain of
In time he learns, however, to make the
optical nerves save the exertions of the
muscles. Then he requires a ping-pony
i ji^jlimii
Not much strength is required in tho
game. A little more vigorous than bil
liards and not quite bo arduous as tennis.
of which it is a cousin german, pins-
THE S U^J)AY CALL.
pcng appeals to those who have the quick
eye.
The skillful player can keep his body
almost rigid, and standing In front of the
table send the ball backward and forward
with scarcely a movement of a muscle
except those of the wrists. Many or the
players are able- to sit In one of the
chairs such as are used by spectators in
billiard games, and still keep the ball go
ing rapidly.
Physicians say that many ping-pong
players suffer from an inflammation of
the eye. and champion players add their
Testimony. The constant watching of the
ball is liable to cause heaoaclies, or, 'in
other words, to cause irritation to spread
from the overworked optical mu.-des.
The pir.g-ro"g eye is often bloodshot.
The only way to cure it is to stop play
ing and to give the overworked eye a
chance to rest. Th!s the ping-pong devo
te*- objects to doing. When ho becomes
absorbed in the game he persists in play
ing it in season and out of season.
There are many ping-pong table's which
served originally in dining-rooms. The
man who plays upon them is prone fo
contract the ping-pong eye. The ideal
table should be dark green^This color is
easy on the eye. A retired billiard or
poo! table is well adapted to the game,
as far*"as the effect upon the eye is con
cerned. The ball is dazzling white. It</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1902-07-13/ed-1/?sp=39&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.211,-0.009,1.376,1.125,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PING-PONG IS THE WARM-WEATHER DIVERSION FOR YOUNG ST. LOUIS SOCIETY MATRONS
	Mrs. Duncan's ptcg-pocg set win he the
i principals of the tennis games to be played
at sight tn Cabasne, With so much to en
tertain the younger society element, it Is
doubtful if many more will Join the earlier
exodus during the month of August. Mrs,
Mae Wiggs has decided to remain at home
to keep house for her father, the genial Pat
Short, who has rent his wife and grand
son away, hut prefer for himself the
comforts of his charmingly appointed
home. Mrs. Wiggs. who calls her father
"son," looks after the cooking herself, an!
leaves even the fascinating ping-pong, at
which she is a adept, to return home n Not eves, tha house dog is foiguttta tfi
Mrs. Duncan's home. Way hack la tha
yard, under a shady tree is a, large atrsara
tank with a canopy oa top to protect tha
bather frost the sun. This Is tha tab la
which Prise. Mrs. Duncan's Mr St. Bs
t.t. takes his dally plunge, The tns Ja
filled with fresh water three times s week.
At the bottom tha tub has a flow-oS. fas
tened with a ecrfc. Any handy hoy eoaW
construct one of these tubs, which has re
tin lining to keep the wood from rottls-g.
Whlle Mrs. Duncan's friends were playing
ping-pong the other afternoon. Prince had
his bath. As he Jumped out and among
tha guests he was not very careful of their
fresh and crisp toilets, but sprayed thira
with the water, which lie shook oat of his
shaggy mane. However, these are incidents
that make things all the more pleasant far
the young matrons, whose healthful recre
ation is the admiration of the few neigh
oars, who, like them, are remaining at
home.</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99066033/1902-08-02/ed-1/?sp=8&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.31,-0.081,1.62,1.62,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>he ping pong craze promises to out
rival the golf fad of previous seasons
In the multitude of things brought out
in the shops which owe their existence
to the fashionable game imported from
London.
Ping pong shirtwaist-sets In silver
consist of a brooch formed of two bats
crossed inside of a horseshoe, and three
pins for the front of the waist made
of two bats crossed.
Ping pong stick-pins have a single
bat mounted on the end of the pin.
The end of a ping pong hatpin is orna
mented with two bats crossed. The de
votee of the ultra-fashionable amuse
ment can proclaim her allegiance by
draping her chapeau with a veil of
white chiffon profusely embroidered In
black with small crossed bats sur
rounded with tiny balls, or the same
design comes embroidered In white on
black chiffon.
Among the special neckwear designed
for the "Ping Pong Girl" is the ping
pong cravat This consists of a stock,
shaped to fit the neck, of heavy corded
white pique finished with long ends,
smartly ornamented on the edge with
lows of stitching, which widen gradu
ally and terminate In a fancy pointed
effect: the ends are double, the one on
top being of pique, beneath which Is
another detached of soft fine mull In
contrasting color, this being slightly
larger, so that when the ends are
crossed and fastened with a scarf pin
the effect Is of a border of color ex
tending beyond the white pique.
The same Idea is carried out In the
ping pong cravat, which comes with
ends already tied in a double knot In
front This Is extremely smart In the
now very fashionable black moire or in
barathea silk ornamented- wlth tows
of stitching, and also In butcher's linen.
These cravats are shown In the various
summer colors.
Another ping pong cravat Is of white
cheviot made with a stock three inches
high and tie graduating Into very wide
ends and embroidered with a design of
crossed bats and balls In black-and-white
or in color. The cravat Is usu
ally worn with ends folded over once
and fastened with a pin.
A ping pong stock of fine, striped,
imported madras has ping pong em
blems embroidered in black, pink, blue
and golf green.
A washable ping pong belt with stock
to match comes in a peculiar fancy
open mesh called Kro-mesh. The
edges are bound with narrow lawn. All
colors are represented, but particular
ly pretty are the all-white mesh belts
and those In different combinations of
blue and white pale blue with white
border, white with pale blue border, a
light blue and white plaid mesh with
white border. A white mesh delicately
barred in green with white binding is
smart as are the black-and-white ef
fects. The gay plaids are quite the
thing for golf. The stock to match Is
of lawn-bound mesh, the ends being
brought around from the back and
tying in a small bow in front
Of course there Is a ping pong shirt
waist It is made In various stuffs,
but the smartest models seen thus far
are of pongee and of butcher's linen.
One of pongee Is in the popular Gib
son style except that it opens down the
front and has a cluster of three one
half inch vertical pleats on each side
of the centre band. The stock and
cravat are of pongee, but what gives
the waist its ping pongy touch Is the
design of crossed bats and balls em
broidered in scarlet on the cravat ends
and on the deep turned-back cuffs. The
symbolical designs embroidered In
black and white on a Gibson model of
green butcher's linen convert it into a
ping pong shirtwaist
Shops are showing ping pong suits,
and If you want to be strictly up-to-date
don't say "polka dot" say "ping
pong dot"
The ping pong craze has even Invad- There
are ping pong tables that can be con
verted Into dining or library tables at
a moment's notice of weathered, Flem
ish or polished golden oak In mission
style; folding tables are of hardwood
for ping pong, the legs and frame of
hardwood with painted and scored tops
made of board that will not warp from
dampness, and there are painted and
scored tops to place over any ordinary
table made of compo board, and ping
pong table covers of green oilcloth,
scored.
For ping pong parties and luncheons
are special table decorations In the way
of souvenirs, favors and other decora
tions which range frombon bon recep
tacles of cardboard In the form of the
bat with a small rubber ball fastened
to the Ud to a tiny box for sweets, the
cover of which when lifted forms a
table covered with green paper to rep
resent the field and ornamented with a
net and ball and racquet the full
fledged table represented in miniature.
Then there is a ping pong thirst
which goes with the game, and a new
punch called ping pong has sprung in
to popularity.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047097/1902-08-09/ed-1/?sp=3&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=0.22,0.374,0.349,0.286,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>If up to dato youll advartiso
Piug poug shoes aud piug potig tics
Ping pong cakes and ping pong
olothea
Ping poug pills aud piug poug hose
Ping pong crackers ping pong
soap
Piug poug cocktails ping poug
dope
Ping poug cigarettes cigars
Ping pong motors ping pong carp
Ping poug tea of ping poug brow
Ping pong ioo crdam soda loi
Piug pong couches piug poug beds
Ping pong nats lor ping pong
lioads
Ping pong gowns for ping pong
girls
Ping pong irons for ping pong curie
Ping poug shirts aud ping poug
sack
Ping poug watoho ping pong
clocks
Piug poug curtains ping pong rugs
Piug poug remedies for bugs
Ping pong hairpins ping pong nails
Ping pong crpata ping pan voils
Ping pong plasters for your corns
Piug poug whistles ping poug
horns
Ping poug goods aud picg pong
trash
Why then youll piug pong lots</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83007243/1957-08-09/ed-1/?sp=6&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.277,-0.078,1.554,1.554,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ping pong is a difficult game for
soccer players to learn. They're
too handy with their feet.
Father William J, Coy, Mary
knoll Missioner from Danvers,
Mass., reports that the youngsters
of his parish here are enthusias
tic ping pong players. The only
trouble is that their games in
variably are called on account of
smashed equipment.
Since the boys began playing
soccer shortly after learning how
to walk, using their feet in
games is second nature to them,
they miss a ping pong ball
with the paddle they automatical
ly catch it with their feet.
"Considering the difference in
size between soccer and ping
pong balls, this is a good trick,"
savs Father Coy. "However, the
difference in hardness is ruining
our garws. Ping pong balls don't
stand up long under such rough
treatment. The bos have a sack
of squashed balls which aren't
worth a bounce on the ping pong
table."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86072192/1902-02-03/ed-1/?sp=6&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.261,-0.076,1.523,1.523,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Ping-Pong, London’s Fad, Captured America.
From the Chicago Tribune.
"Ping, pong; ping, pong, ping, pong;
ping, pong; ping—"
Then Instead of a "pong" there Is a
shuffling of feet, the snap of a small,
shell-llke ball on the floor, an exclama
tion from some one—and when the person
who has Just opened the street door at
Spalding's turns his attention to the ex
treme left of the house, he sees a rect
angular table, 8 feet long and 4 feet wideN
with a miniature tennis net stretched
across the center; ons person is standing
at the table holding a miniature racquet
,in his hand, while the other player, with
a similar racquet. Is chasing a white ball
an Inch and a half In diameter, which
has rolled away some where out of sight.
And at Spalding's they say that In 1600
dining rooms belonging to the Chicago so
ciety this "ping pong” Is reverberant sev
eral evenings a week; that Chicago’s 400
calls It table tennis; ajid that Mrs. Pot
ter Palmer bought the flrst four sets
placed on sale In the house. Since that
time the factory at Springfield, Mass.,
has not been able to turn the parapher
nalia ot the game out nearly fast enough
to supply the Chicago demand^
It la conceded now, too, that since the
advent of the dear little Pinky Panky
Poo belonging to Mrs. Patrick Campbell
and the inevitable importation of English
"ping pong," as the fashionable name
for this parlor tennib, the fates them
selves could not stop the march of these
alliteratlves.
For "parlor tennis” In Chicago Is the
game of “ping pong.” which has driven
London society frantic; which is sweep
ing English conservatism Into garbage
heaps, srnd which already Is taking its
place In current literature with allthedlg
nlty which once belonged to whist, chess,
and the bank at Monte Carlo. London
(society has ben stampeded by ping pong.
Only now and then does society literature
enter Its protests, as does a pessimistic
contributor to the Christmas Sketch. This
Iconlclast Bays:
"And inside the library Sir John brood
ed, and with determination. What a
confoundedly rascally game ping pong
was, anyhow. Why had he not insisted
on drawing room croquet as the least of
a doxen disagreeable evils? The parch
ment In the ping pong racquet had now
become strained to concert pitch by the
heat of the dining room, and the Bound
had changed from an aggravating dull
contralo to a piercing soprano which rat
tled on his eardrums like the reports of
rlflo shots.
"Family festivities always struck him
ns peculiarly melancholy now. It made
him miserable to be so happy. The only
real use of these games was that they
kept the younger boys from smoking
cigarettes and from dissipating generally.
Perhaps If Clarence had been there he
might have endured the racket without
much suffering. To be sure Clarence
used to turn the place into a bear garden,
but what a merry laugh he had. Ho he
used to—'"
The paragraph breaks there, and only
so far is ping pong considered in philo
sophic light. But ping pong was. is. and
will be in London for a good while to
come, and it is spreading in tjie United
States generally with the rapidity of
smallpox in an unvaccinated Mexican vil
lage.
"It’s the ball that has made the game,"
said a salesman. "Table tennis in Chi
cago is old, but It didn’t take because in
playing it the regular tennis ball was
used. It was heavy, too big, and gener
ally unresponsive. The ball, you see, Is
of white celluloid, thin as an eggshell
and as lively as a greased flea. A play
er hardly can touch it lightly enough to
keep it In the bounds of a 9-foot table.
This leaves table tennis just enough an
after dinner game to aid digestion, as
the lightness of the racquets and of the
ball leaves the exertions of the play less
than those of dancing.’</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016244/1957-06-26/ed-1/?sp=10&q=ping-pong&st=text&r=-0.237,-0.074,1.473,1.473,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Pong Tourneys
Beginning in July, a new ser
ies of ping pong and pool tour
naments will be held at the USO
YMCA.
Under the supervision of the
program director, the pool tour
neys will be handled by Leo Crow
ley, and the ping pong events by
Dr. Sol Perolman, both experts
in their fields.
The following plan has been set
up:
Each tournament will be car
ried out over a period of six weeks,
one tourney per week fn both
ping pong and pool.
The winners of the greatest to
tal score in pool and the highest
place in ping pong will be award
ed trophies, properly engraved,
at the end of the six weeks.
The trophies are on display in
the program office of the USO
at the present time.
The club has recently had a
face lifting and as well as being
newly painted and repairs, the
addition of new furniture includ
ed two new ping pong tables. This
will help the tournament facili
ties immensely.
All servicemen are cordially in
vited to enter these tournaments
every Tuesday night.
Individual prizes for first and
second place are given each week;
the trophy is a grand prize for
the series’ winners.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
	
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-heroin-crisis</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022472/1912-12-13/ed-1/?sp=5&q=State+Board+Strive+Stamp+Drug+Abuses+Heroin&st=text&r=-0.293,-0.051,1.626,1.33,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>STATE BOARD WILL STRIVE TO STAMP OUT DRUG ABUSES
	PtesMent John A. Leverty of the
estate Board of Pharmaoy OommiMlon
ra stated to a. Fumar reporter today
that th board stands ready to aot
agalxust th sal of opium, heroin and
other narvating drags In cases where
specific ahargu are brought. The
board takes Jurisdiction upon th
ground that it has discretionary pow-
-violated.
There is no law In this State against
the sale of morphine or its derivatives
iu.t the board is of the opinion that
th pharmacy laws are not intended
to provide a meani for victims of
drag habits to purchase drugs with
.Immunity.
Concerning the recent case in this
-c3tjF -where the board took aotlon Pres
ident leverty stated: "We would not
have been able to take action If spe
cific charges had not been made.
There ie no doubt there are a large
number of heroin users in Connec
ticut, but the sellers of the stuff (If
4T-tifrfiital cannot be Dunished bevond
the revocation of their pharmacy li
censes until the legislature enacts a
itatute similar to the oocaina law.
The crusade being conducted in
JJfew York against heroin has made
this state a haven for the users of the
drug. New Haven has passed an or
dmanoe against the sale of the stuff
nd the result is that the users are
coming to Bridgeport to purchase.
"Already there is a substitute for
heroin on the market. It is called
dlonln' ethyl morphine hydrochlorate)
ana the law that does not cover all
?i-u mm of a morphine derivative will
Have little effeot in stamping out the
""n" understand that the Bridgeport
aldermen are to pass an ordinance at
Its next meeting. If they specify
heroin alone and do not specify all
drugs of a morphine derivative they
will leave loopholes for the users to
crawl through."
"Bing" Is the slang name of the
drug used bv the drug slaves here. It
Is estimated that there are between
pno and 400 users of the drug in this
oity Its line is said to have been
first introduced here by habitueB of
mo nnderworid. -who taught the possi
bilities of producing soothing sensa
tions to young men and boys they
mt in lunch rooms and pool and bil
liard halls. The drug users are now
-i n h found among factory work
ers and clerks who carry the stuff
in the sawea on iuu aa. luuuiam
Heroin is said to produce a, feeling
that makes the user feel as though
he owned the world and its users loose
their aopetlte for food while their
craving for tobacco in cigarette form
increases. Increased doses are needed
from time to time to satisfy the de
sires. The stuff is expensive and one
young man who is employed In a
n'rf End factory recently went to
;Nw Tork and bought $18 worth of
the stuff, spending nis enure pay mr
a. week in order to have a supply on
hand.
Rarelv a month passes without at
least one death in this city directly
traceable to the ravages of the drug
habit.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87055779/1913-12-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Fink+Prescibed+Dope+Heroin+Prescription+Druggists&st=text&r=-0.198,-0.07,1.396,1.396,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>SAY THAT DR. FINK PRESCRIBED DOPE
	The state
board of medicad registration and ex
amination will meet here Tuesday to
hear evidence against Dr. II. A. Fink,
a prominent South Bend physician,
charged with prescribing heroin for
minors. The action is for a revocation
of Dr. Fink's license.
The charge was liled by attorneys
for 2"sewton Ilolycross, a South Bend
contractor, who charges the prescrip
tion was given his son, Raymond, by
Dr. Fink. The boy is said to have
purchased the dru -at Paul Wolter's
drug store in South Bend on the pre
scription. The charge is iilcd under the act
passed by the legislature at the last
session in which heroin was put on
the "black list" and physicians forbid
den to prescribe the drug to u-i ir.
A short time ago, it is charged,
yonng Ilolycross' parents noticed he
was acting peculiarly, as if under the
influence of a drug. After close ques
tioning the boy is said to have broken
down and admitted the purchase of
tho drug through the prescription,
naming- the physician. The charges
were prepared immediately and filed
with the state beard.
Raymond Ilolycross was one of the
boys involved in the -drug" expose
in South Bend last winter when sev
eral South Bend druggists were ar
rested charged with furnishing the
"dope" to minors. The cases were
dismissed, however, when it was found
the statute did not cover the particu
lar drug, heroin, which the boys had
been taking. They were lirst sup
plied the drug through an Assyrian,
Solomon Neimer. it was claimed, who
acted as a purchasing agent.
The agitation resulting from this
expose was the cause of the introduc
tion of the bill to prohibit the sale
or prescription of heroin to persons
known to be users.
The act provides that a physician
shall lose his license if convicted of
prescribing the drug to an habitual
user. In criminal proceedings a line
of $ur or not more than 5G00 and im
prisonment in the county jail not le
than io days or inr- than a year, is
provided for the lirst offense. For the
second offense the line is not less than
$-j00 or more than 51.00 and im
prisonment in the penitentiary from
one to eight years.
Druggists who sell heroin on pre
scription must keep a record of such
sales and report to the state board of
pharmacy.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1914-09-14/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Slave+Drugs+Nerve+Destroying+Substances+Heroin+Drug+Victim&st=text&r=-0.225,-0.072,1.449,1.449,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>BOY OF 19, SLAVE OF DRUGS, SEEKS TO BEGIN NEW LIFE
	Tells Amazing Story of the
Ease With Which He
Was Able to Buy Nerve
Qestroying Substances.
Twenty-four houra out of a potlco cell,
a toy of 1. Pale, thin anl hardly able to
uK one foot after the other, told today
),ow he took to uslni? cocaine and heroin
nd what the drug have done to him In
the Iwo yeara.he has been their victim.
William Schaffer, 822 Olive street, Is the
hoy He was arrested as a. disorderly
character. Magistrate Tracy, at the
Eleventh and Winter streets station, gave
him his freedom yesterany. ouuy -Klns
his light against tho drugs.
chaffer Is a flaxen-hnlred youth who
n fairly sturdy In the dayB before ho
began experimenting with heroin. Ho
weighed about HO pounds then. Today
ills weight Is down to 120 and tho clothes
he wears are sizes too large, though once
they ntted him. His head hangs weakly
and he has trouble walking moro than a
few steps.
Schaffer has been treated twice for tho
drug habit. Onco It was In tho House of
ri i pctlon. where he sreved three month
nfter stealing from a department store to
get money for the drugs. A month ngo
he was discharged as cured from the
mlladelphla Hospital.
"But ou can't keep away from It
.around here," Schaffer explained, as he
told his stoo. "I kept away from the i
drugs two weeks nnd then two men Held
gome heroin before me. I've been pretty
bad since then."
His being "pietty bad" resulted In an
attack of heart failure, which caused his
arrest. When Patrolman MoKonna, of
the Eleventh nnd Winter streets Btatlon,
found that Schafter was not drunk, tho
boy was sent to tho Hahnemann Hos
pital and then back to tho police station.
"J had a close call," said Schaffer. "I
was filled with heroin and cocalno all day
and a convulsion got me. That's the way
they all die," he added, shaking his head.
Scharter can clear up me mHiery inai
surrounds the making of 17-ye.ir-old co
caine fiends.
"Hard to get cocaine? Well, I should
say not'' he exclaimed. "I never had
any trouble buying all I wanted when I
had the money. Did they mind selling to
a boy? They did not. I could show you
a good many drug stores where you can
buy It now. But most of It comes from
the cocaine peddlers.
"J started taking drugs Just about two
y fiats ago I used to stay around a pool
room at Eighth and Vine streets. Tho
fellows In there asked mo If I didn't want
to try some heroin. So I did. I took it
every day for a month and then I thought
I'd stop. But I couldn't"
Tho only limes since then that the
Schaffer boy has lived without drugs have
been the periods Just following his re
lease from hospitals.
"1 worked for some chemists at Eighth
aiid Callowhlll streets when I first began
lifllng the stuff," Schaffer went on. "But
7 couldn't hold on long after the habit
fcot Yne. I started taking one tablet of
one-sixth of a grain a day, Saturday I
took 35 tablets.
"Of course, I didn't always have money
to buy heroin. I used to steal things from
department stores when I needed money.
Once you get tho habit you can't go more
than three or four hours without heroin.
"I used to take little things from the
counters and I never got caught. But
Inst march I picked up somo Jewelry and
they caught mo out on tho lHvnik."
Schaffer was sentenced to three months I
In the Houso of Correction for that. p
rtieasea on June 6 and then got work A SELF-CONFESSED BOY DRUG VICTIM
William Schaffer, who tried heroin "to see what it was like," tells how boys
are made drug fiends and his own experiences trying to break the habit.
man. Ho held some heroin undor my
nose and then 1 Just had to buy It. They
sell two tablets for a nickel. Since then
I have been taking 25 or .10 tablets a
day."
Schaffer says he has taken heroin for
tho last. "I'm scared," he declared. "I
know what happens nnd thoy all die when
they get like I am. I'm going to stop,"
Schaffer thinks getting out of tho city
to a farm Is the best way to keen from
Using more drugs.
"But what chance havp I got'?" he
akcd. "I don't know where I enn go.
Sure, I know lots of other young fellows
who are taking drugs. How old are they?
Oh, 16 nnd 17 and some younger, Any
one can huy the stuff If thoy know where
to go."
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045389/1915-02-17/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Harrison+Drug+Act+Effect+Drugs+Heroin&st=text&r=-0.232,-0.073,1.464,1.464,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>HARRISON DRUG ACT TAKES EFFECT MARCH 1
	In compliance with the Harrison drug
act, approved on Dec'cmbcr 17, 1914,
prescribing tho manner In which cer
tain hablt-formlng drugs shall be
manufactured or dispensed, the United
mates Internal Revenue ofTlco Is ready
to Issue the special stamps and order
Ijlanks which the law provides. Every
physician, druggist, dentist and veter
inary surgeon handling any of the
drugs coming under the Harrison act
is required to register with the Col
lector of Internal Revenue previous to
March 1. A heavy penalty is prescribed
for nil those coming under tho pro
visions of tho aspecial stamps bv March 1, If they
have in their possession any opium or
roru leaven, their salts or derivatiesT
or any preparation manufactured from
tliem. Collector Moncure has made ar
rangements with the various division
deputy' collectors to have placed In
the hands of all those who come under
the act the necessary application blank,
known as form 678. Upon receipt by
the collector of the application the
registry number -will be Klven, and
every physician. drugKist, dentist and
veterinary surgeon will he required to
make tho order under his registered
number. t Is required by the act that every
person who produce.", imports, manu
factures, _corn pounds, deals In, dispenses,
'?Up. distributes or gives away opium
?r coca leaves or any compound of
liber, shall register It's name or style,
place or places of business, and, if lie
ban no office, then bis residence. No
physician, dentist or veterinarian may
have In bis possession or write a pre
scription for any opium or cocaine
preparation unless he has first reg
istered with the collector of Internal
ievenue of bin district and has paid
the tax of n. Aft'-r compliance with
tlils formula he will bo required to
use on every prescription for the drugs
named. In order to b.iy any of them,
the serial number Klven him. lie musrt
make out a duplicate of every order
or prescription, and keep the duplicates
on file for at leant two years
The prescription must be written,
signed by the prescriber's name in
full and be dated as of the. day 11
signed, and must show the pre
server's serial number and the loca
tion of bis office and the name and
address of the patient for whom It
Is Issued. The prescriptions must not
be refilled.Kvery person, firm or com,>aty dis
pensing directly to consumers any of
the drugs referred to must keep an
accurate inventory of all such atock
as ho has on band, anJ must verify
the Inventory by oath not later than
March 5.
According to the pamph'.e; issued by
the' State Board of Pharmacy the act
absolutely prohibits Tho sulo of lauda
num, Squlbb's Mixture, Sun Cholera
<"'ure, Dovers's I'owder, codeine and
preparations containing more than two
grains of opium, one-fourth grain of
morphine, one-eighth grain of heroin
or ono Kralti of C0'lei'>e to the ounce,
except upon the prescription of a
doctor registered under the act, or upon
the revenue order blanks; and these
preparations may no longer be sold by
merchants and retail dealers. Posses
sion of any of th?so drugs, oxcept in
compliance with the act, will lie con
sidered presumptive evidence of a vio
lation of the act.
The penalty for violation of any of
the requirements of the acts is a fine
of not more than f^'.OOO or Imprison
ment for not more than five years, or
b?th, in the discretion of the court.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045389/1916-05-28/ed-1/?sp=48&q=Widows+Son+Ruin+Ruined+Drugs+Heroin+Drug&st=text&r=-0.251,-0.052,1.436,1.436,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>RUINED THE WIDOW’S SON - MUST PAY HER DAMAGES
	A MOTHER brings this action against a drug firm for having
sold to hor -minor son a certain poisonous drug known as
?heroin. She alleges that as a jesult of these sales her
son became an habitual U6er of heroin and thereby became a
physical and moral wreck, unable to perform any labor and that
his health -was ruined and his mind destroyed, whereby she was
deprived of his services and. has been greatly damaged. The
facts were submitted'to a jury and a Verdict returned in favor
?f the plaintiff for $2,000 compensatory damages and $1,000
punitive damages. Our examination of tne records convinces us that the num
erous sales of this drug to this boy continuing over a long
period of time have been established by overwhelming evidence.
And we believe that the evidence shows that the plaintiff was,
in fact, actually damaged. The proof showB that" previous to his
acquisition of the drug habit the young man earned considerable
money.t establishes that the defendants. Impelled by the ln3tlnct
for gain and profit, absolutely disregarding the health and future
of this young man, and wholly unmindful of the consequences to
his parents, sold him this drug and continued to sell it to him
long after they discovered Its deleterious effects upon his system.
To say that they did this innocently affronts the reason. These
defendants were pharmacists, skilled in the science of mixing
drugs; they knew their purposes, usee and effects. They knew
the subtle, sinister destructive effect on the human syBtem of
Ihis offspring of opium. They knew of its malicious and uncon
querable mastery over the human mind?knew of its inexorable
demands upon Its victlmB.During the time which these defendants were sup
drug to a young man he "became a vagabond, an id!
fiend and a criminal; undutiful to his mother, wortfnl
self and dangerous to the community. The Jury w
concluding that all this was the result of the Illicit tri
on by these defendants and that they should be pi
their reckless disregard of the rights amT welfare
and his mother.IN awarding a mother, a widow, 53,000 damages against
a druggist who sold to lier son, a minor, quantities
of heroin during a period of several years, a Su
preme Court jury sitting in Schenectady, New York, has
established a precedent making it just as criminal to
destroy the efficiency of a boy as it would be to injure
a man's property, his horse' or cow.
Hitherto persons who sold to young men drugs or
alcoholic drinks which damaged their health could bo
prosecuted only on the legal technicalities prohibiting
the sale of drugs without a prescription or the sale
of drugs to minors.elling "dope" was unanimously upheld.
In the opinion written by Justice Wesley O. Howard,
of Troy, In which four other judges concurred, it is
stated that the evidence produced in this particular
case proved that the mother of young Rooney had
been actually damaged. Inasmuch as previous to the
boy's demoralization through the drug habit he had
earned considerable money, and that in the deprivation
of services to which she was legally entitled the prop
erty rights of the mother had been trespassed upon.
"The plaintiff bases her claim upon the same prin
ciple which underlies the cause of action accruing to
a father In case of the abduction of his daughter, or
to a husband In case of the alienation of his wife's
affection," declared the-judges. "Precedent is not nec
essary in order that the plaintiff may recover here.
If the rights of the plalntift have been Invaded; there
must be redress."
According to this decision any parent whose son is
sold drugs or alcohol to such a degree that his char
acter and efficiency are destroyed may take action
against the olfendcr for the actual damage done.
Judge Howard and his confrere's decision makes it
as criminal to undermine a boy's health by selling
him drugs as it is to administer poison to a neighbor's
horse.From a happy-dispositioned boy, al
ways eager to help his mother and to be of service
to hit, employers, he dovdoped into a vagabond, a
retusing to work, stealing whatever he could
in ordet r; secure the drug. He became physically de
formed. his character became insolent, ugly,, morose
and sullen.' Hie health ruined to the degree that he
was unable to perform any labor, his mind destroyed,
this boy, in whom a mother once took tender pride,
has goue alotg a road to ruin leading through the
Schenectady County Jail, the Albany Penitentiary,
the Fonda Jail to the Elmlra Reformatory, where ha
Js at present confined.Before his eyes, week by week and month by month,
this druggist could not fail to see the ghastly effects
of the poison he -was purveying?the fading of color
in the boy's cheeks, tho growing sallowne-ss of the
complexion, the rings deepening under his dull, sullen
eyes, the palsied tremor of his arms as he reached for
the drug. He could not have failed to see the villainy
working?no more than the poisoner who deliberately
watches his victim, no less than the saloonkeeper who
sells whiskey to young men day by day over a bar.According to Justice Howard, the proof furnished
abundantly established that the druggists, "impelled
by the instinct for gain and profit, absolutely disre
garding tlie health and future of this young man, and
wholly unmindful of tho consequences to his parents,
sold him this drug and continued to sell ii to him
long after they discovered its deleterious effects upon
his system." For the pills sold the druggist received
seventy-five cents a hundred. On the single sale of
one thousand pills?enough to kill one hundred per
sons?they received $7.50.
Shortly after the theft of a large quantity of raw
heroin by young Rooney from another drugstore in
Amsterdam, the boy's cousin, James Murry, was found
dying in the. .Rooney house from drug poisoning. It
is believed by local authorities that his death was
due to an overdose of heroin. In the legal proceedings
it was brought out that the heroin habit had been
contracted by a number of other young men ia
Schenectady. Young Hooney's mother, at present em
ployed as a clerk in a department store in Schenec
tady, admitted in court that she had expended her
entire savings of $2,000 in endeavoring to reform
her son.
The story of young Roonoy's downfall can possibly
be duplicated in many other communities where young
men are sold drugs by unscrupulous druggists. Leo
liooney at the age of eighteen possessed much of the
natural curiosity of youth. When, about four years
ago, William Slavin, a pal, told him wonderfully pleas
ant dreams could be obtained by taking a certain
drug, Rooney was anxious to try it. He Avas given
several pills and?being totally Ignorant of the hide
ously destructive effects of this product of opium?
said he would ,like to get more.
According to the testimony furnished in court,
Rooney was taken by his friend to tho drugstore of
C. B. Skinner Co., No. 8 East Main street, Amster
dam, which Is fifteen miles from Schenectady, and was
Introduced to C. B. Skinner as being "all right."
On January 1, 1912, ho made his first purchase of
heroin tablets, securing two hundred tablets, for
which he paid $1.50. These tablets were sold to him
without his presenting a physician's prescription, nor
was his name entered on the "poison book" in the
store. After his first purchase the boy, according to
his declaration, bought plllB regularly almost every
week up until June 5. 1914, a period of nearly two and
a half years.
Month by month the fatal power of the drug took
hold of him and he became a confirmed user of the
dope. He sometimes took from six to eight pills an
hour. His purchases averaged from three hundred to
six hundred pills a week. Sometimes hiB dally con
sumption was ae high as seventy-flve to one hundred
tablets. One week he made the astounding purchase
of oue thousand tablets. These tablets were all one
twelfth or one-eighth of a grain each. During the
proceedings brought by the boy's mother against the
druggist it was testified that on no occasion did Skin
ner placo the pills in a bottle bearing a poison label
as Is required by law.
C. B. Skinner, the druggist accused, has been a
pharmacist since 1892. He graduated from the
University of Buffalo in 1S98. The other member of
the firm, S. W. Skinner, is in charge of a drug store
in Illon, N. Y. This concern, accuhed of selling to a
young boy one thousand heroin tablets in a single
week for the sum of $7.50, is reported to be worth
$40,000.
In November, 1912, the boy declared that Druggist
Skinner asked him if his mother knew that he was
using heroin. "Not to my knowledge," he answered.
Itooney's mother, however, began to observe a change
in the boy's appearance. Day by day he was afflicted
by what seemed an increasing sickness. His com
plexion became sallow, his eyes deep and sunken.
When walking the streets he would sometimes stop,
andr leaning against a post, fall into a profound slum
ber in the daytime. From a hoalthy, athletic, Greet
young man he began to show signs of a deformity.
He no longer walked erect, but stooped constantly.
He became sluggish and indolent;' his temper was
sullen and irascible.
The boy had always been industrious. His mother
had come to Schcnectady from Leadville, Colorado,
in August, 1903, and sent Leo to school until he was
sixteen. While attending school he sold newspapers,
and afterward worked for a while for a clgarmaker.
He then secured employment with the General Elec
tric Company at a salary of $50 a month. The boy
had a voice of extraordinary quality and was in de
mand at local entertainments. He often earned from
$10 to $15 a week by singing.
Until the drug took hold of him he was most solici
tous about his mother and attended to all the house
hold chores. His mother was hurt and perplexed when
the time came that he refused to carry coal from the
cellar. One day he had told her that he had given up
his position. Duriug the day he slept most of the time
and at nights stayed away. Sometimes he was absent
from his home for an entire week. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1916-09-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Dope+Fiends+Doctors+Drugs+Drug+Heroin+Druggists&st=text&r=-0.217,-0.072,1.434,1.434,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DOPE FIENDS USE DOCTORS TO GET DRUGS
	The preceding article on the menacing
tprtad of the narcotic drug" evil have dealt
ivUh Ut general effect!, the crippling of the
Harrison net by court decltlom, the emug
gltng o "dope" In greet Quantifies info the
city by a criminal syndicate and the degra
dation of young men and women by Ten
derloin dwellers co-optratlng with this vn
dlcate. Today' article reveals the danger
from untcrtipulons doctors and show n
need of more drastio regulation of drug
dispensing. The inquiry by the livening
Ledger was, undertaken at the request of
Dr. Horatio O. Wood, Jr., and with the ac
tive co-operation of United Btatet District
Attorney Kane's ofIce.
By HENRY JAMES BUXTON
When the Coroner of Philadelphia looked
Into the facts attending the death ot a
youth named Tony riova, less than a week
ago, ha was led to exclaim that if no other
remedy for the cancer called 'The Arsenal
could be found It should be burned down.
From Uie little Tenth street pie shop, two
or threV blocks north of Market, the boy
had been carried suffering from the effects
of heroin. He died In a hospital a few
hours later.
A special policeman calmly observed at
the Inquest that "dope parties" were fre
quently held. In "The Arsenal" and that in
a recent raid twenty-nine persons were re
moved from tho place, all but two under
the influence of narcotic drugs.
In cases like these the hand ot the "dope
syndicate" la clearly seen. Through an
.Intricate smuggling system It Imports Into
this city many 'rmndrod pounds of mor
phine, cocaine and heroin monthly and dis
tributes them through Tenderloin agents
and even from autos that pass through
various sections on schedule time: This syn
dicate was facing extinction under the Har
rison act, which forbids the sale of "dope"
'except on a -physician's prescription. It
gained a new lease qf life through the re-
.cent' decision, invalidating 'section 8 ,of.C&
act. for this, prevents the conviction, of those
found with the drug In their possession,.
declaring that the mere possession of largs
quantities of a drug is not evidence pre
sumptive of guilt.
HOW 120 "FIENDS" GOT DRUGS
Legislation is required to stop this enor
mous leak In the wall raised against the
flood ot evil sustenance for crime and
degradation. But tt-'moro difficult problem
presents Itself In the evading of the law
by unscrupulous physicians.
Dr. Frank M. Hendrlck, a negro physi
cian, of 1912 Dickinson street, was arrested
qn' A'ugust 8 by Deputy Internal Revenue
Collector McDevltt, accused of supplying
120 young "dope fiends" of South Phila
delphia with heroin, the most vicious of
modern habit-forming drugs. McDevltt and
Glovanl, a detective In the employ of ths
State Pharmaceutical Department, testified
that Doctor Hendrlck wrote heroin pre
scrlptlons for tha drug addicts under ths
pretense that, he was attempting to curs
them by the ''reduction method."
During seventy-eight days Hendrlck
wrote 1000 such prescriptions, and tor each,
one he obtained a tee of $1, making a total
of 11000 In a little more than two months.
The prescriptions were filled by two drug
gists, Samuel H. Toplan and Solomon Bay
llnson. These two druggists were also
placed under arrest, accused of having
made illicit sales to drug victims.
Tbplan and Bayllnson received 81 each
for the prescriptions tor heroin filled by
them. That -makes a grand total ot $2009
paid by the group ot 120 for their supply
during seventy-eight days. McDevltt testi
fied that the addicts who patronized Doctor
Hendrlck and the druggists ranged in ag
from sixteen to twenty-Ova years. One of
them was an eighteen-year-old boy, a high
school graduate, who was employed In ths
plant ot tbe Remington Arms Company at
116.60 a week. This boy waa giving $14 of'
his salary eaclweek to Doctor Hendrlck
and the two druggists to fe "cured" of the
heroin habit.
A mother In South Philadelphia told Mc
Devltt that her boy had become useless
sines he acquired vtho heroin bablt He,
too, went to Doctor Hendrlck.
OETTINO THE EVIDENCE
Glylng a fictitious nams and address,
Glovanl called on Hendrlck, and -asked hiss
to write him a prescription for 10 grain ot
heroin. Doctor Hendrlck asked how long
he used the drug. ''Six months," was ths
reply. Ths physician asksd If he desired
to be cured. The detective .ril4 la U
afrirmatlveXand recslvsd a prsosriptlon, for
20 grains ot heroin after he h4irnsd hi
name In a little reeerd ,bko4evanl hud
the prescription filled -without 'awdtfrVeuHjr -at
Bayljnson's'drug store,</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1919-04-28/ed-1/?sp=4&q=Drug+Evil+Ogden+Drugs+Heroin+Narcotic&st=text&r=0.203,0.29,0.399,0.326,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>DRUG EVIL IN OGDEN AND ELSEWHERE
	A dispatch dated April 21, from Washington, D. C,
states that federal officials will urge our reprcsentati cs
at the peace conference to endeavor to secure an interna
tional arrangement for the enforcement of anti-narcotic
laws, this action being, in their opinion, demanded by the
increased use of narcotic drugs in the United States and
the difficulty expeiienced in controlling their distribution.
The dispatch also states that the people of the United
States use five times as much narcotic drugs per capita as
do the people of China, and it is feared that, with the ad
vent of prohibition, the number of drug addicts will greatly
increase unless the most rigid measures are taken to sup
press the traffic. In this connection, Daniel C. Roper, com
'L missioner of revenue, in his annual report says, "Compre
hensive and effective administration of the narcotic laws
must be based upon an international pcrspectie, support
ed by international agreements, and co-operative interpre-
tion or policy under which the drug world trade may be
adequately policed." Secretary of the Treasury Glass, of
whose department the internal revenue bureau forms a
part, will forward a statement regarding this matter to the
president within the next few days. The report of Repre
sentative Henry T. Rainey, chairman of the committee to
investigate the use of drugs in the United States, has been
ready for sometime but the figures contained in it are so
alarming that it has been held up by the treasury depart
ment officials for the purpose of careful verification be
i fore it is published. The report shows more than 1,500.
000 narcotic drug addicts in the United Stales, of which
number New York City is said to have nearly 300,000.
It may be true that this country has more users of narcotic drugs
than any other country, but that weakness has developed over a long
Ij period of years during which whiskey has been openly sold in nine
Jmi! tenths of the states in very large quantities, and may we not make
wl'1 the deduction that whiskey has paved the way for drugs?
These "drug" stories arc being circulated as a defense of whiskey.
They may prove to be boomerangs.
For years the American people have been trained to resort to
drugs. But it is our opinion that the cocaine, morphine and opium
habits have decreased since those drugs have been legislated against
by the federal government.
Ogden, up to six years ago, had shivering, shaking men and women
f who. in their nervous twitching! as they went about the streets, dis
closed they were victims of strong drugs. Our jails always had one
H or more of the unfortunates. Of late there has been no outward evi
dence of this debasement, and. if Ogden is not the exception, we are
justified in saying that the drug evil is rapidly decreasing in the Unit-</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1922-03-19/ed-1/?sp=44&q=drugs+opium+narcotic+contraband+heroin&st=text&r=-0.392,-0.016,1.766,1.445,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>PURSUING OPIUM SELLERS IN NEW YORK
	I wous Pqlice Commissioner, Richard Z.
bRight, and Special Deputy Police Com
misoner Carleton Simon. With their feet
an the grimy furnace room floor and their
ames red from the glow of the open fire-box,
the stood and watched more than three
million and, a half dollars' worth of for
bidden drugs thrown in on to the glowing
coals. 0
:!*Am In one fom' or another or chemi
as derivatives of opium made up most of
that valuable but contraband collection. It
represented a little less than a year's accu
mulation of the Narcotic Division of the
New York police force under the command
of'Special Deputy Commissioner Simon.
It the detectives were able to find and
confiscate such a quantity of dope in a
year's time it must, of course, represent
but a small percentage of the actual amount
of forbidden drugs which are brought into
Ne.w York City and consumed in a twelve
uonth. It was a startling evidence of the
widespread use of drugs. and the impres
sive spectacle sobered the faces of Com
missioner Enright and his deputy. and de
termined them to. pursue the wicked traffic
with even greater vigor.
In addition to the assortment of raw
opium, prepared opium, morphine, heroin
cocaine and other contraband drugs there
was an extraordinary assortment of opium
pipes and "hop layouts," hypodermic need
lea and other things used by drug ad
licts. All these were thrown into the fire
box of the furnace
"Well, it is hard to estimate the real
value to the community of what we have
destroye4 here to-day.' said Commissioner
Simon as he tossed the last package of
drugs Into the furnace. "Not all drug ad
dicts are criminals, but most criminals are
drug addicts. We have destroyed enough
drugs to-day to put half of Greater New
York to sleep. No one can say how many
drug-crased criminals and crimes of crafti
ness and violence have been averted by
the seisure and destruction of all this
stuff."
It is the drug that inspires the crafty
schemes in the minds of highwaymen, bur
glars, confidence men and murderers, and
gives them the courage to do their des
perate work. A group of criminals, ,for
instance, will "lie up" for the night in
some hidden den, smoking opium. Out of
the fumes will come an idea for swindling
a rich and innocent widow, perhape, or a
plan for holding up a paymaster or blow
ing a safe.The idea still seems feasible-but it re
quires courage'-rat like courage-to carry
it out. Normal men-even criminals not
under the influence of drugs-would lack
the nerve to commit the crime. But the
"hop-heads" do not give up; they know
how they can get the nerve. A jab of the
hypodermnic needle, a sniff of cocaine or
heroin-and they are stemulated, madly,
unreasoningly, to the point where nothing
/oan stop them.Photograph of Part of the Threi
Opium Pipes and Layouts Seizei
son them. Drugs not only stimulate crime,
but Intensify it. And the drug evil is
growing, as the police know. Specific lo
calities may nt realize it, but throughout
the country officers of the law are coming
to recognise the drug traffic as one of the
main roots of the evils with which they a
constantly contend.
Drugs make criminals in more than one
way. Not only does the use of drugs tend
to 'destroy the mental resistance to evil
that is called morals, but drugs seem to
make their victihna insensible to the differ
ence between right and wrong. Drugs
now cost so much money that the addict
is usually compelled to resort to crime in
order to buy them. Many a criminal has
committed his first offense in order to
buy his "dope.' 'Commissioner Simon
says that the average drug fiend pays $5
a day. $35 a week for his supply. He has
arrested addicts who confessed to paying
as high as $16 a day.
in the sixteen months that Dr. Simon
has been in offii4 his Narcotic Division has
made about 4,000 arrests. The record for
this year is well ahead of that for a corres
ponding period last year'which does not
mean that the drug evil is increasing out
of all bounds in New York City, but mere.
ly that the Narcotic Division is increasing.
ly efficient in keeping pace.
Under the State law anyone caught with
drugs illegally in his possession may be
arrested and sent to take "the cure"-a
scientific treatment administered in a
State institution, where the patient is
given diminishing doses of his drug, fed
according to prescribed dietary, and made
to exercise until eventually he has lost the
"habit" and is well ad strong enough
mentally and physiaally to be released.
The cure really cure., but, unfortunately,
underworld vietims return to teirs oldMIlisougl h cvr and fDl arreWot
of drug usern that Dr. Simon's men get to
the drug peddlers-the men they are really
after. The drug addict tells the police
where he buys his supply, or they shadow
him until they find out for themselves.
Then, pretending to be drug fiends them
selves-every detective in the Narcotic
Division can give an excellent imitation of
a "cokey" or a "hop-head"-they persuade
the peddler to sell them the drug. Then
he is arrested, or his depot raided. It was
the spoils of these raids that went into
the furnace--except for several thousand
dollars' worth still awaiting use as evi
dence in court.
Where does all this drug come from?
The Federal law forbid, its importation
except under bond. The Treasury Depart
ment has a force of men at work to pre
vent it being smuggled in-too small a
force to cover the lengthy borders and sea
coast of the country. Much of it comes
from E~urope. Dr. Simon. who has agents
in England and the Continent, discovered
'recently that the Germans were manufact
uring heroin and cocaine synthetically,
and that they and a Japanese syndicate
were planning to flood the United States
with their products. There is no law in
Germany or Japan to forbid the exporta
tion of narcotics.
A good deal of dope has found its way
to New York recently from Canada, which
in turn got it from Mezico. By the
arrest in New York a few weeks ago of a
Montreal criminal and opium user Dr.
Simon verined informaion comhag to him
from other sources, namely, that the drug
ring in Montreal has been using chorus
girls playing in Montreal to smuggle drugs
over the ,order.in this practise; one of the women re
ferred to above had a large clientele in
fashionable hotels and made a specialty
of boosting the drug among college
students.
Etnee ball bh~tnas number taany drug
boosters; others pes as chorus girls. If
thir m'W are of the higher planes
et sesely they seldom fall within the
clutches of the police, because there is
emough mosey available to buy the drug
without resorting to crime. In the last
few weeks, however, CommissIoner 8imon
has ten down some of the peddlers who
supply the upper West, Side, the Murray
Hill section and Fifth avenue with drugs,
and wealthy iwera of narcotics are finding
It more difficult to-get their daily dope.
One of these peddlers had a route as
dedinite as that of a milkman. Begiag
at six every morning he made his seuads
of famissmable aparment houses, leaving
three decks of cocaine here, a phial of
morphine there, half a deon decks of
heroin at the nelt place. Sometimes, his
books showed, he was called on to supply
additional opium or heroin for a "perty,"
just as a catorer might supply dinners
a. a edding. ,It en a tato s e w al=One of the greatest forward steps in the
war on drugs is the founding by Dr.
Simon of a central clearing house for the
photographs and records of drug users and
peddlers. He is in correspondence with
the police authorities in more than 300
cities here and in Europe, and exchanges
with them the dossiers of anyone found
to be engaged in the drug traffic. A few
days ago Dr. Simon's men arrested a Los
Angeles addict who had been in New York
only eight hours.</text>
      </result>
	    
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85035720/1924-01-19/ed-2/?sp=6&q=heroin+crisis+%281898-1922%29&st=text&r=-0.191,-0.069,1.382,1.382,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92051126/1913-02-06/ed-1/?sp=5&q=heroin&st=text&r=-0.212,-0.071,1.424,1.424,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>"I do not believe that the public
appreciates the extent to which this
heroin has gone. Hospitals in Bridge
port and New Haven average about
two new cases a month among its vic
tims. One of tho worst features of the
heroin habit is that it practically in
capacitates a person from doing work.
Most of the people addicted to it are
in fact recruited from the class who
do not work and most of our heroin
users today have served time in our
county jails. One of my patients
claims to have acquired the habit
there and states that heroin was
passed along from prisoner to pris
oner in a secret way in order to pro
vide a stimulant that would act as a
substitute for the alcoholic liquors
they could not get.“Last year,” continued Dr. McDer
mott, a city ordinance forbid the
sale of heroin In this city and most of
'our worst fiends here took up their
abode in Bridgeport, where there was
nothing to prevent the druggists from
selling it, or they had messengers
bring it to them. In fairness to tho
druggists of our city I must state em
phatically that even before this law
went into effect the great majority of
them refused to sell this drug. About
two months ago the sale of heroin
was stopped in Bridgeport and since
then the supply has been passed out
by street venders and unscrupulous
persons who have been able to ob
tain large quantities of the drug from
wholesale houses.
In this city these street tenders ply
their trade in Church street between
Crown and George and many persons
have been surprised to know how
these individuals seemingly live so
well without working. One of these
venders, a former New Havener, who
sells the drug on the streets of Bridge
port, has made the claim that he con
siders it a very poor day when
he does not sell from $100, to $150
worth of it. This, at first ‘SeefhS like
an exaggerated statement and. I was
loth to believe it, until 'oiSpatients recently told me that he was
in the habit of paying $16 for 1,000
one-sixth grain tablets of heroin and
that he used on an average over 300
of them a day. This patient acquired
$6,000 last July and has squandered
$3,700 of it since that time on
heroin.
“The users after they have acquired
the heroin habit cannot work and
spend most of their time either under
the influence cf this drug or going
about looking for it. One of these
fiends told me that when the law stop
ping the sale of heroin in Bridgeport
went into effect that men and even
women victims of the habit were
known to give battle on the streets of
Bridgeport for possession of the drug.”
Dr. McDermott says there is a place
in Congress avenue where it is sold
even today and that the fellow engag-^
ed in this traffic has a peep hole in the
door of his home and when a pros
pective buyer appears he takes a good
look at him first and if he has the ear
marks of being a victim of the habit he
will sell him the drug. Dr. McDermott
believes that nothing short of a state
wide, if not a nation wide larw, prohib
iting the sale and manufacture of this
pernicious drug, will stop the growth
of this evil which is increasing by
leaps and bounds. He says that such
a law should contain a heavy prison
penally because no mere fine, however
large it may be will deter the heroin
seller when one considers the enormous
profit that can be made out of this
business.
Continuing Dr. McDermott said:
“I am firmly convinced that a great
many of the thefts and burglaries we
have had in this city recently have
been the work of heroin victims who
unable to obtain the wherewithal to
obtain this drug, have resorted to these
most desperate means to obtain money
enough to buy it.
They will rob anything and put It in
pawn and with the money thus ob
tained they will buy the drug. It is a
very bad state of affairs and one which
should be dealt with by the authorities
at once.”
</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064057/1913-12-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=heroin&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.077,1.533,1.533,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>GREAT MANY USE HEROIN
Taking of Narcotic Spreading
Among Drug Fiends.
Laws Against Sale of Morphine and
Cocaine Leading Those With Habit
to Take Up Even More Dan
gerous Substances.
Washington.-According to informa
tion gathered by the United States de
partment of agriculture, there has
been a sudden and very significant
increase in the use by persons with
a drug habit of the little-known but
very dangerous drug called "heroin."
The sales of this drug have recently
increased greatly. particularly in those
states which have rigid laws prevent
ing the indiscriminate sale of mor
phine and cocaine. investigation of
the subject establishes the fact that
many drug victims who formerly used
morphine and cotaine and who under
the new laws find it ditticult to obtain
these substances have begun using
heroin, the sale of which is not as
yet as carefully restricted under state
laws. The drug is said to be fully as
dangerous as morphine and by many
is held to be much worse. for the rea
son that it occasionally kills the vic
tim outright and its habit is far
harder to overcome than the use of
the other drugs. The department,
pending further action, specially
warns all people who are unfamiliar
with the drug to avoid all prepara
tions containing the substance and to
Heroin, the consumption of which
by drug takers has recently increased
so markedly, is a derivative of mor
phine, the opium alkaloid. It is known
in chemical parlance as diacetyl mor
phine, and it is frequently found as a
constituent of a number of proprietary
drugs. Its use seems to be especially
notable in parts of Pennsylvania.
This year the coroner's office in Phila
delphia county has held inquests on
five sudden deaths from heroin poison
ing. In each case the victim was a
heroin fiend and was on a heroin de
dauch and took an overdose. The sub
stance apparently is far more danger
ous for drug users than morphine or
cocaine. Drug fiends apparently are
able to consume relatively large qualn
titles of the other two drugs, but any
sudden and material increase in the
amount of heroin taken is very liable
to prove fatal. As indicating the wide
sale of this substance, it is known that
one druggist in Pennsylvania whose
store was located in an undesirable
section of his city has been buying
heroin tablets. The word 'heroin" on any labi
should be regarded as a danger sig
nal</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022472/1913-12-05/ed-1/?sp=5&q=heroin&st=text&r=-0.177,0.002,1.326,1.085,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Heroin, the consumption of which
by drug takers, has recently increas
ed so markedly,- is a derivative of
morphine, the opium, alkaloid. it is
known in chemical parlance as dla-
cetyl -morphine,, and"-ft Is freauently
found as a constituent of a number of
proprietary drugs.. Its use seems to
be especially notable in parts of Penn-.
sylvania. This year the. coroner's of
fice in Philadelphia county has held
inquests on "five sudden deaths from
heroin poisoning.' In each case the
victim was a heroin fiend and was on
a heroin debauch and took an over
dose. The substance apparently is
tar more dangerous for drug users
than morphine or cocaine. Drug
liends apparently are able to consume
relatively large quantities of the oth
er two drugs, but any sudden and ma
terial increase in the amount of her-
oin taken is very liable to prove fa
tal. As indicating the wide sale -of
this substance, it is known that one
druggist in Pennsylvania whose; store
was located in an undesirable section
of I113 city, has .been '.buying heroin
tablets in 25,000 iots.
The labels of proprietary and other
medicines purchased by laymen should
be carefully scrutinized for a state
ment which is' required by the. Na
tional Food and .Drugs Act of the
quantity or proportion of heroin, or
any derivative or preparation thereof.
The word "heroin" on any label
should be regarded as a danser sig
nal, according to the experts of the
Department.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075258/1947-06-04/ed-1/?sp=9&q=heroin</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
